<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	>

<channel>
	<title>PI Testimonial &#8211; Boston Biomedical Innovation Center</title>
	<atom:link href="https://davekuhar.github.io/bbic/category/pi-testimonial/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>https://davekuhar.github.io/bbic/</link>
	<description></description>
	<lastBuildDate>Wed, 16 Nov 2016 22:11:16 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>
	hourly	</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>
	1	</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>https://wordpress.org/?v=5.8.1</generator>

<image>
	<url>https://davekuhar.github.io/bbic/wp-content/uploads/2016/11/cropped-bbic-favicon-32x32.png</url>
	<title>PI Testimonial &#8211; Boston Biomedical Innovation Center</title>
	<link>https://davekuhar.github.io/bbic/</link>
	<width>32</width>
	<height>32</height>
</image> 
	<item>
		<title>Testimonial: Resolving Hurdles</title>
		<link>https://davekuhar.github.io/bbic/2016/10/27/resolving-hurdles/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[B-BIC]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 27 Oct 2016 21:26:54 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[PI Testimonial]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://b-bic.org/?p=433</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>The B-BIC program has been instrumental in helping us accelerate development of our bioreactor and achieve commercial proof of feasibility that would not have been possible within the same time frame by traditional non-dilutive funding mechanisms available at the time. B-BIC also allowed us to bridge academic and commercial requirements and resolve many practical hurdles&#8230;</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://davekuhar.github.io/bbic/2016/10/27/resolving-hurdles/">Testimonial: Resolving Hurdles</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://davekuhar.github.io/bbic/">Boston Biomedical Innovation Center</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>The B-BIC program has been instrumental in helping us accelerate development of our bioreactor and achieve commercial proof of feasibility that would not have been possible within the same time frame by traditional non-dilutive funding mechanisms available at the time. B-BIC also allowed us to bridge academic and commercial requirements and resolve many practical hurdles to facilitate the spin out of private company from an academic lab.</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://davekuhar.github.io/bbic/2016/10/27/resolving-hurdles/">Testimonial: Resolving Hurdles</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://davekuhar.github.io/bbic/">Boston Biomedical Innovation Center</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Testimonial: Challenging Interaction a Huge Plus</title>
		<link>https://davekuhar.github.io/bbic/2016/10/27/challenging-interaction-a-huge-plus/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[B-BIC]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 27 Oct 2016 21:25:37 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[PI Testimonial]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://b-bic.org/?p=432</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Here is how B-BIC has helped this project. The money itself. It would be very difficult to raise money for this project from standard sources. Challenging questions from the reviewers. During the review of our preproposal, one challenge from the B-BIC point of contact was that we should design a Phase 3 trial for our&#8230;</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://davekuhar.github.io/bbic/2016/10/27/challenging-interaction-a-huge-plus/">Testimonial: Challenging Interaction a Huge Plus</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://davekuhar.github.io/bbic/">Boston Biomedical Innovation Center</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Here is how B-BIC has helped this project.</p>
<ol>
<li>The money itself. It would be very difficult to raise money for this project from standard sources.</li>
<li>Challenging questions from the reviewers. During the review of our preproposal, one challenge from the B-BIC point of contact was that we should design a Phase 3 trial for our product and see whether, with a reasonable number of patients, we could generate the statistical power needed to prove our product was superior to current EPO products. This is a very commercially focused question that an academic reviewer would never ask. It took us a long time to get the answer. However, it came in very handy in a recent investor pitch, in which an outside expert (who had run EPO clinical trials) asked me the same question and I was immediately able to answer it.</li>
<li>Back-and-forth with the reviewers, being able to respond to their comments. Doing this has also helped us understand the kind of questions that investors ask, and have ready answers. Also, clinician reviewers had a completely different take on our science than we did. We needed to significantly adapt our story to reach both of these audiences.</li>
<li>Evaluation based driven by the commercial opportunity</li>
</ol>
<p>To sum up, the challenging back-and-forth interaction with B-BIC people has been a huge plus. It has helped us prepare for investor meetings, and also helped us bridge the gap between our own reductionistic protein engineering worldview and that of clinicians.</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://davekuhar.github.io/bbic/2016/10/27/challenging-interaction-a-huge-plus/">Testimonial: Challenging Interaction a Huge Plus</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://davekuhar.github.io/bbic/">Boston Biomedical Innovation Center</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Testimonial: Clear Objectives</title>
		<link>https://davekuhar.github.io/bbic/2016/10/27/clear-objectives/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[B-BIC]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 27 Oct 2016 21:24:14 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[PI Testimonial]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://b-bic.org/?p=431</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>B-BIC has been a communicative and supportive organization to work with and the program is well designed. B-BIC has chosen targeted topics and emphasized commercial translation, making the program objectives clear. This aids the proposer in assessing likelihood of winning an award. The involvement of the program managers has been helpful and informative. The proposal&#8230;</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://davekuhar.github.io/bbic/2016/10/27/clear-objectives/">Testimonial: Clear Objectives</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://davekuhar.github.io/bbic/">Boston Biomedical Innovation Center</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>B-BIC has been a communicative and supportive organization to work with and the program is well designed. B-BIC has chosen targeted topics and emphasized commercial translation, making the program objectives clear. This aids the proposer in assessing likelihood of winning an award. The involvement of the program managers has been helpful and informative. The proposal evaluation and feedback prior to award was very thorough and I am grateful for the effort that went into that.</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://davekuhar.github.io/bbic/2016/10/27/clear-objectives/">Testimonial: Clear Objectives</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://davekuhar.github.io/bbic/">Boston Biomedical Innovation Center</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Testimonial: Business Principles Advanced</title>
		<link>https://davekuhar.github.io/bbic/2016/10/27/business-principles-advanced/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[B-BIC]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 27 Oct 2016 21:23:18 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[PI Testimonial]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://b-bic.org/?p=430</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>This grant has enabled me to advance the development of a medical device with a high potential clinical impact. This is consistent with my academic career, which centers on translational imaging research. The B-BIC grant has allowed me to engage with marketing and business advisors to learn more deeply about practical business principles necessary to&#8230;</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://davekuhar.github.io/bbic/2016/10/27/business-principles-advanced/">Testimonial: Business Principles Advanced</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://davekuhar.github.io/bbic/">Boston Biomedical Innovation Center</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>This grant has enabled me to advance the development of a medical device with a high potential clinical impact. This is consistent with my academic career, which centers on translational imaging research. The B-BIC grant has allowed me to engage with marketing and business advisors to learn more deeply about practical business principles necessary to navigate our device towards FDA approval and clinical use.</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://davekuhar.github.io/bbic/2016/10/27/business-principles-advanced/">Testimonial: Business Principles Advanced</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://davekuhar.github.io/bbic/">Boston Biomedical Innovation Center</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Testimonial: Broadened Horizons</title>
		<link>https://davekuhar.github.io/bbic/2016/10/27/broadened-horizons/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[B-BIC]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 27 Oct 2016 21:13:39 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[PI Testimonial]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://b-bic.org/?p=429</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>This project has advanced my professional development objectives by allowing me to learn much about the technology development and commercialization process. Beyond my conventional academic pursuits, involvement with the B-BIC program has broadened my horizons and underlined the importance of translating promising science from our laboratories towards practical/commercial applications. This work has enhanced my interest&#8230;</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://davekuhar.github.io/bbic/2016/10/27/broadened-horizons/">Testimonial: Broadened Horizons</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://davekuhar.github.io/bbic/">Boston Biomedical Innovation Center</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>This project has advanced my professional development objectives by allowing me to learn much about the technology development and commercialization process. Beyond my conventional academic pursuits, involvement with the B-BIC program has broadened my horizons and underlined the importance of translating promising science from our laboratories towards practical/commercial applications. This work has enhanced my interest in continuing to pursue these lines of efforts, enabling our science to impact society.</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://davekuhar.github.io/bbic/2016/10/27/broadened-horizons/">Testimonial: Broadened Horizons</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://davekuhar.github.io/bbic/">Boston Biomedical Innovation Center</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Testimonial: Increased Visibility</title>
		<link>https://davekuhar.github.io/bbic/2016/10/27/increased-visibility/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[B-BIC]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 27 Oct 2016 21:12:49 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[PI Testimonial]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://b-bic.org/?p=428</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Progress made under this award has increased my visibility to pharmaceutical companies so that I have been sought as an investigator for several companies.</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://davekuhar.github.io/bbic/2016/10/27/increased-visibility/">Testimonial: Increased Visibility</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://davekuhar.github.io/bbic/">Boston Biomedical Innovation Center</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Progress made under this award has increased my visibility to pharmaceutical companies so that I have been sought as an investigator for several companies.</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://davekuhar.github.io/bbic/2016/10/27/increased-visibility/">Testimonial: Increased Visibility</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://davekuhar.github.io/bbic/">Boston Biomedical Innovation Center</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Testimonial: Program Invaluable</title>
		<link>https://davekuhar.github.io/bbic/2016/10/27/program-invaluable/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[B-BIC]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 27 Oct 2016 21:03:47 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[PI Testimonial]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://b-bic.org/?p=427</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>The B-BIC program has been invaluable in two ways. First, the grant support has allowed us to bring our device from early prototyping stage to full preclinical testing and now at a point where we can focus on achieving FDA clearance for clinical use. Second, the support of advisors have taught me to navigate the&#8230;</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://davekuhar.github.io/bbic/2016/10/27/program-invaluable/">Testimonial: Program Invaluable</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://davekuhar.github.io/bbic/">Boston Biomedical Innovation Center</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>The B-BIC program has been invaluable in two ways. First, the grant support has allowed us to bring our device from early prototyping stage to full preclinical testing and now at a point where we can focus on achieving FDA clearance for clinical use. Second, the support of advisors have taught me to navigate the various stages of device development from a practical business development perspective, which I now understand to be as critical as scientific proof-of-concept in transitioning any device from benchtop research towards bedside application.</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://davekuhar.github.io/bbic/2016/10/27/program-invaluable/">Testimonial: Program Invaluable</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://davekuhar.github.io/bbic/">Boston Biomedical Innovation Center</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
