<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	>

<channel>
	<title>Greg Mueller &#8211; Boston Biomedical Innovation Center</title>
	<atom:link href="https://davekuhar.github.io/bbic/author/gmueller/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>https://davekuhar.github.io/bbic/</link>
	<description></description>
	<lastBuildDate>Wed, 16 Nov 2016 22:16:21 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>
	hourly	</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>
	1	</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>https://wordpress.org/?v=5.8.1</generator>

<image>
	<url>https://davekuhar.github.io/bbic/wp-content/uploads/2016/11/cropped-bbic-favicon-32x32.png</url>
	<title>Greg Mueller &#8211; Boston Biomedical Innovation Center</title>
	<link>https://davekuhar.github.io/bbic/</link>
	<width>32</width>
	<height>32</height>
</image> 
	<item>
		<title>Success Story: Warren Zapol, David Zapol and Third Pole, Inc.</title>
		<link>https://davekuhar.github.io/bbic/2016/10/25/warren-and-david-zapol-third-pole-inc/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Greg Mueller]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 25 Oct 2016 14:57:16 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[BBIC Collaborative]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Success Stories]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://b-bic.org/?p=309</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Approximately 10,000 “blue babies” are given inhaled nitric oxide (NO) to treat Hypoxic Respiratory Failure each year. Other potential uses for inhaled NO include heart attacks, strokes, and malaria. But the technology necessary to deliver inhaled NO is available only in a limited number of countries, for those who can afford it, with physicians who&#8230;</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://davekuhar.github.io/bbic/2016/10/25/warren-and-david-zapol-third-pole-inc/">Success Story: Warren Zapol, David Zapol and Third Pole, Inc.</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://davekuhar.github.io/bbic/">Boston Biomedical Innovation Center</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Approximately 10,000 “blue babies” are given inhaled nitric oxide (NO) to treat Hypoxic Respiratory Failure each year. Other potential uses for inhaled NO include heart attacks, strokes, and malaria. But the technology necessary to deliver inhaled NO is available only in a limited number of countries, for those who can afford it, with physicians who have access to it.</p>
<p>Warren Zapol and his team invented a technology that produces NO without using tanks that has been shown to be equivalent to current tank-gas NO. David Zapol founded a company, Third Pole, Inc., to develop and commercialize the technology. After receiving the B-BIC award, Third Pole was able to evaluate a range of early prototype configurations, identify and prioritize areas of technology development and engage the expertise to address these challenges. Third Pole was also able to secure angel investment along with two SBIR awards that have helped them start hiring and search for their own lab space.</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://davekuhar.github.io/bbic/2016/10/25/warren-and-david-zapol-third-pole-inc/">Success Story: Warren Zapol, David Zapol and Third Pole, Inc.</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://davekuhar.github.io/bbic/">Boston Biomedical Innovation Center</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Success Story: Jonathan Thon and Platelet Biogenesis, Inc</title>
		<link>https://davekuhar.github.io/bbic/2016/10/25/jonathan-thon-and-platelet-biogenesis-inc/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Greg Mueller]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 25 Oct 2016 14:56:11 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[BBIC Collaborative]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Success Stories]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://b-bic.org/?p=308</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Platelets are the ‘bandaids’ of the bloodstream. They are the cells in your blood that stop you from bleeding and transfusions save the lives of millions every year. However, platelets can only be stored for 5-7.5 days because of bacterial contamination issues. To manage this, blood centers typically don’t keep more than a 1.5 days&#8230;</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://davekuhar.github.io/bbic/2016/10/25/jonathan-thon-and-platelet-biogenesis-inc/">Success Story: Jonathan Thon and Platelet Biogenesis, Inc</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://davekuhar.github.io/bbic/">Boston Biomedical Innovation Center</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Platelets are the ‘bandaids’ of the bloodstream. They are the cells in your blood that stop you from bleeding and transfusions save the lives of millions every year. However, platelets can only be stored for 5-7.5 days because of bacterial contamination issues. To manage this, blood centers typically don’t keep more than a 1.5 days of platelet in inventory. The risk of depletion and collection challenges eliminate 24% of the stock. This shortfall is exacerbated during emergencies when platelets are most needed.</p>
<p>The solution is scalable production of pluripotent stem cell-derived (donor-independent) human platelets. With B-BIC’s support, Jonathan and the Platelet Biogenesis team engaged a contract design group (should we name them?) to help them scale their ability to produce platelets using a microfluidic bioreactor. They also gathered input from blood bankers about platelet unmet needs and pricing data from CMS to refine their business plan, which helped them secure a Direct to Phase II SBIR award. Since exiting B-BIC, they have moved into their own space and started hiring the staff needed to continue their scaling work and initiate animal trials.</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://davekuhar.github.io/bbic/2016/10/25/jonathan-thon-and-platelet-biogenesis-inc/">Success Story: Jonathan Thon and Platelet Biogenesis, Inc</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://davekuhar.github.io/bbic/">Boston Biomedical Innovation Center</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
