<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	>

<channel>
	<title>Tips &amp; Tricks &#8211; Boston Biomedical Innovation Center</title>
	<atom:link href="https://davekuhar.github.io/bbic/category/tips-tricks/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>https://davekuhar.github.io/bbic/</link>
	<description></description>
	<lastBuildDate>Tue, 17 Apr 2018 11:20:42 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>
	hourly	</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>
	1	</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>https://wordpress.org/?v=5.8.1</generator>

<image>
	<url>https://davekuhar.github.io/bbic/wp-content/uploads/2016/11/cropped-bbic-favicon-32x32.png</url>
	<title>Tips &amp; Tricks &#8211; Boston Biomedical Innovation Center</title>
	<link>https://davekuhar.github.io/bbic/</link>
	<width>32</width>
	<height>32</height>
</image> 
	<item>
		<title>Tips &#038; Tricks:  Regulatory Path</title>
		<link>https://davekuhar.github.io/bbic/2018/04/17/tips-tricks-regulatory-path/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[B-BIC]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 17 Apr 2018 11:20:42 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Tips & Tricks]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Regulatory]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Tips]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Tricks]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://b-bic.org/?p=1124</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Create an outline of the regulatory plan that will enable marketing approval of your technology/product. Determine which FDA division is likely to have oversight for development and approval by visiting www.fda.gov as direct consultation with the appropriate FDA Division is an essential step to ensure the smoothest possible design and conduct of a development plan&#8230;</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://davekuhar.github.io/bbic/2018/04/17/tips-tricks-regulatory-path/">Tips &#038; Tricks:  Regulatory Path</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://davekuhar.github.io/bbic/">Boston Biomedical Innovation Center</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<ul>
<li>Create an outline of the regulatory plan that will enable marketing approval of your technology/product.</li>
<li>Determine which FDA division is likely to have oversight for development and approval by visiting <a href="http://www.fda.gov/">www.fda.gov</a> as direct consultation with the appropriate FDA Division is an essential step to ensure the smoothest possible design and conduct of a development plan that will lead to approval.</li>
<li>To determine the class of your device you need its regulation number.  The regulation number can be found through the FDA classification database or through the FDA device panel to which your device belongs.</li>
</ul>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://davekuhar.github.io/bbic/2018/04/17/tips-tricks-regulatory-path/">Tips &#038; Tricks:  Regulatory Path</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://davekuhar.github.io/bbic/">Boston Biomedical Innovation Center</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Tips and Tricks: Defining Your Market</title>
		<link>https://davekuhar.github.io/bbic/2018/03/01/tips-tricks-defining-market/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[B-BIC]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 01 Mar 2018 13:35:56 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Tips & Tricks]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://b-bic.org/?p=1119</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>A “top-down” analysis is based on current technologies or products that address the medical need your technology/product is intended to address, and the market defined by their sales figures. The bottom-up analysis starts with identification and enumeration of the specific target patient population your technology/product will address.  What is the patient population and what are&#8230;</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://davekuhar.github.io/bbic/2018/03/01/tips-tricks-defining-market/">Tips and Tricks: Defining Your Market</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://davekuhar.github.io/bbic/">Boston Biomedical Innovation Center</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<ul>
<li>A “top-down” analysis is based on current technologies or products that address the medical need your technology/product is intended to address, and the market defined by their sales figures.</li>
<li>The bottom-up analysis starts with identification and enumeration of the specific target patient population your technology/product will address.  What is the patient population and what are the trends projected over the development of your product and its lifetime on the market?</li>
<li>It is important in the pricing decision to consider who your customers and decision-makers will be. Each of these stakeholders may value your technology/product differently, so their roles and opinions will have to be factored into the pricing projection.</li>
<li>CoGS will be a key factor in development decision-making, with low-cost choices made to limit CoGS.  In the medical device field, the price typically needs to be four times CoGS to generate reasonable profit.</li>
<li>When you have an estimate of target patient numbers, price, and CoGS, you can do some simple math to get a revenue and profit forecast.</li>
</ul>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://davekuhar.github.io/bbic/2018/03/01/tips-tricks-defining-market/">Tips and Tricks: Defining Your Market</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://davekuhar.github.io/bbic/">Boston Biomedical Innovation Center</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>TIPS AND TRICKS:  Defining Your Competitive Landscape</title>
		<link>https://davekuhar.github.io/bbic/2018/01/31/tips-tricks-defining-competitive-landscape/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[B-BIC]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 31 Jan 2018 21:25:46 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Tips & Tricks]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://b-bic.org/?p=1102</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>The first step in defining your competitive landscape is to identify and define the technology’s current competition and how they fit into or define current standard of care (SoC). An important step in the process is to forecast how is the SoC landscape may shift during your technology/product development. Identify other technologies/products in development that&#8230;</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://davekuhar.github.io/bbic/2018/01/31/tips-tricks-defining-competitive-landscape/">TIPS AND TRICKS:  Defining Your Competitive Landscape</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://davekuhar.github.io/bbic/">Boston Biomedical Innovation Center</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<ul>
<li>The first step in defining your competitive landscape is to identify and define the technology’s current competition and how they fit into or define current standard of care (SoC).</li>
<li>An important step in the process is to forecast how is the SoC landscape may shift during your technology/product development.</li>
<li>Identify other technologies/products in development that may emerge as strong competitors in the future, and may alter SoC and the way your technology/product would fit in.</li>
<li>The key to competitive analysis is differentiation: how is your proposed technology/product better than current and other future options, and for what segment(s) of the patient population?</li>
</ul>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://davekuhar.github.io/bbic/2018/01/31/tips-tricks-defining-competitive-landscape/">TIPS AND TRICKS:  Defining Your Competitive Landscape</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://davekuhar.github.io/bbic/">Boston Biomedical Innovation Center</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Tips &#038; Tricks: Explaining Your Proposed Solution</title>
		<link>https://davekuhar.github.io/bbic/2017/12/11/tips-tricks-filling-unmet-need-proposed-solution/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[B-BIC]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Mon, 11 Dec 2017 13:34:46 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[News]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Tips & Tricks]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Tips]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Tricks]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[unmet need]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://b-bic.org/?p=1063</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Understand the population you are targeting and why.  It may be preferable to define a narrower niche for your entry to the market. Consider where your device/drug will be administered and by what means.  This choice will greatly influence the preclinical and clinical development needs and strategies. Most investors will want to see proof-of-concept (POC)&#8230;</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://davekuhar.github.io/bbic/2017/12/11/tips-tricks-filling-unmet-need-proposed-solution/">Tips &#038; Tricks: Explaining Your Proposed Solution</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://davekuhar.github.io/bbic/">Boston Biomedical Innovation Center</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<ul>
<li>Understand the population you are targeting and why.  It may be preferable to define a narrower niche for your entry to the market.</li>
</ul>
<ul>
<li>Consider where your device/drug will be administered and by what means.  This choice will greatly influence the preclinical and clinical development needs and strategies.</li>
</ul>
<ul>
<li>Most investors will want to see proof-of-concept (POC) data that extends beyond early discovery research. Provide evidence that your device or drug will be efficacious and can successfully make its way to the market by using a solid scientific foundation.</li>
</ul>
<ul>
<li>Be sure to describe the current physician practice/standard treatment and discuss how the new drug/device will be an improvement worthy of a change in the clinical setting.</li>
</ul>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://davekuhar.github.io/bbic/2017/12/11/tips-tricks-filling-unmet-need-proposed-solution/">Tips &#038; Tricks: Explaining Your Proposed Solution</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://davekuhar.github.io/bbic/">Boston Biomedical Innovation Center</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Tips &#038; Tricks:  Defining Your Need Statement</title>
		<link>https://davekuhar.github.io/bbic/2017/11/10/tips-tricks-defining-need-statement/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[B-BIC]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 10 Nov 2017 17:17:15 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Tips & Tricks]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Tips]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Tricks]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[unmet need]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://b-bic.org/?p=1040</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Contributed by Josh Tolkoff An unmet need is more than an incremental improvement and once it exists in the market &#8211; it makes a substantial change for the better. Talk with many stakeholders (patients, clinicians, hospital administrators, hospital purchasing agents, insurance providers, etc.) to better understand the need, and determine what kind of solutions would&#8230;</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://davekuhar.github.io/bbic/2017/11/10/tips-tricks-defining-need-statement/">Tips &#038; Tricks:  Defining Your Need Statement</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://davekuhar.github.io/bbic/">Boston Biomedical Innovation Center</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Contributed by Josh Tolkoff</p>
<ul>
<li>An unmet need is more than an incremental improvement and once it exists in the market &#8211; it makes a substantial change for the better.</li>
</ul>
<ul>
<li>Talk with many stakeholders (patients, clinicians, hospital administrators, hospital purchasing agents, insurance providers, etc.) to better understand the need, and determine what kind of solutions would fit in the current clinical environment.</li>
</ul>
<ul>
<li>Think about the fundamental objective of the device, therapeutic, process, procedure, diagnostic, etc. and broaden your thinking about innovative ways to completely change the nature of the problem.</li>
</ul>
<ul>
<li>Observe, write down problems, broaden your thinking to develop need statements.</li>
</ul>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://davekuhar.github.io/bbic/2017/11/10/tips-tricks-defining-need-statement/">Tips &#038; Tricks:  Defining Your Need Statement</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://davekuhar.github.io/bbic/">Boston Biomedical Innovation Center</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Tips &#038; Tricks:  Writing your B-BIC Proposal or Business Plan Overview</title>
		<link>https://davekuhar.github.io/bbic/2017/10/30/tips-tricks-writing-b-bic-proposal-business-plan-overview/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[B-BIC]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Mon, 30 Oct 2017 15:36:05 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Tips & Tricks]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[business plan]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[overview]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[PROPOSAL]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://b-bic.org/?p=1018</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>The best way to begin an overview is by presenting a clear picture of the problem that needs to be solved.  Aim to tell a narrative story about the specific problem that patients or clinicians are currently experiencing. Address a specific disease or healthcare management issue, and include key facts to show the potential market size. Define&#8230;</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://davekuhar.github.io/bbic/2017/10/30/tips-tricks-writing-b-bic-proposal-business-plan-overview/">Tips &#038; Tricks:  Writing your B-BIC Proposal or Business Plan Overview</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://davekuhar.github.io/bbic/">Boston Biomedical Innovation Center</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<ul>
<li>The best way to begin an overview is by presenting a clear picture of the problem that needs to be solved.  Aim to tell a narrative story about the specific problem that patients or clinicians are currently experiencing.</li>
<li>Address a specific disease or healthcare management issue, and include key facts to show the potential market size.</li>
<li>Define your proposed solution and how it will solve the problem.</li>
<li>Understand and articulate existing alternatives for solving the problem and show how the solution you are presenting offers compelling advantages over these alternatives.</li>
<li>Write a first draft when you begin, and re-write as you go through the process of completing the B-BIC proposal/Business Plan.</li>
</ul>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://davekuhar.github.io/bbic/2017/10/30/tips-tricks-writing-b-bic-proposal-business-plan-overview/">Tips &#038; Tricks:  Writing your B-BIC Proposal or Business Plan Overview</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://davekuhar.github.io/bbic/">Boston Biomedical Innovation Center</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>FAQ:  B-BIC APPLICATION PROCESS</title>
		<link>https://davekuhar.github.io/bbic/2017/05/15/faq-b-bic-application-process/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[B-BIC]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Mon, 15 May 2017 13:40:56 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[FAQ]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Tips & Tricks]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[APPLY]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[PROPOSAL]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://b-bic.org/?p=813</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>&#160; Who can apply for B-BIC grants? Anyone holding a faculty appointment at a B-BIC member institution may apply for a B-BIC grant. May I submit more than one application? Applicants may submit more than one proposal to both the Pilot and DRIVE programs.  However, each application must have a distinct set of aims and&#8230;</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://davekuhar.github.io/bbic/2017/05/15/faq-b-bic-application-process/">FAQ:  B-BIC APPLICATION PROCESS</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://davekuhar.github.io/bbic/">Boston Biomedical Innovation Center</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p><b>Who can apply for B-BIC grants?<br />
</b>Anyone holding a faculty appointment at a B-BIC member institution may apply for a B-BIC grant.</p>
<p><b>May I submit more than one application?</b></p>
<p>Applicants may submit more than one proposal to both the Pilot and DRIVE programs.  However, each application must have a distinct set of aims and work plan.</p>
<p><b>Is there a limit to the number of applications I can submit?</b></p>
<p>B-BIC encourages and supports the entrepreneurial personality.  Investigators are encouraged to re-apply with proposals for different applications of the same technology as well as new technologies.  Early determination of technology failure is part of the process.</p>
<p><b>Should I disclose any unprotected proprietary information in the submission? </b></p>
<p>Do not disclose any unprotected proprietary information.  Protecting proprietary information is the responsibility of the applicant and the applicant institution. Pharma and device companies are actively involved in the center providing expertise and supporting the development of commercial outcomes.</p>
<p><b>Who reviews the applications?<br />
</b>B-BIC reviewers include practicing clinical specialists and domain experts, engineers and scientists with broad experience in medical innovation, external business development and commercialization experts, and our Federal partners at the FDA, CMS, USPTO, and NIH.</p>
<p><b>Who retains the rights to any intellectual property generated by a proposal? </b></p>
<p>Management of intellectual property is determined by the policies of the institution responsible for the application.  Investigators funded by B-BIC are expected to establish IP with their institution’s technology transfer office, with an indication that B-BIC funding has been used to support their work.</p>
<p><b>Who do I call for help if I have questions about proposals or awards?</b></p>
<p>The B-BIC main office number is 857-307-2440.  Email may also be sent to Lesley Watts, B-BIC Director for Administration and Finance, at <a href="mailto:lwatts@partners.org">lwatts@partners.org</a>.</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://davekuhar.github.io/bbic/2017/05/15/faq-b-bic-application-process/">FAQ:  B-BIC APPLICATION PROCESS</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://davekuhar.github.io/bbic/">Boston Biomedical Innovation Center</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Tips &#038; Tricks: Customer Research Basics</title>
		<link>https://davekuhar.github.io/bbic/2017/04/24/tips-tricks-customer-research-basics/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[B-BIC]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Mon, 24 Apr 2017 13:06:04 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[News]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Tips & Tricks]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Paul Tessier]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Tips]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://b-bic.org/?p=806</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>The “build it and they will come” approach may have worked for Steven Jobs at Apple but does not work for most new products.  For us mere mortals, it is important to conduct customer research before proceeding too far with a new idea.  You want to know if there is a market for your product&#8230;</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://davekuhar.github.io/bbic/2017/04/24/tips-tricks-customer-research-basics/">Tips &#038; Tricks: Customer Research Basics</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://davekuhar.github.io/bbic/">Boston Biomedical Innovation Center</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>The “build it and they will come” approach may have worked for Steven Jobs at Apple but does not work for most new products.  For us mere mortals, it is important to conduct customer research before proceeding too far with a new idea.  You want to know if there is a market for your product and what you might do to make the product better. The thought of contacting potential customers might be intimidating, but it is not as hard you might think with the right approach.</p>
<p>First, identify what you believe to be your potential customer target demographics.  Who are they?  Where are they located?  You may have a few customers to consider: the end user, a buyer (someone in a purchasing department), or a distributor. Then identity what you believe is important to each customer and develop a discussion outline. Different customer types will have different knowledge and interests. Once you have customers identified, take a look through your contacts and see if you have any mutual relationships to help make an introduction if needed. Then reach out to healthy sample within in each group</p>
<p>Remember, this is not a sales pitch.  Saying anything like “I have this fantastic new product that does XYZ, don’t you just love it” will quickly put the person on guard and may shut down the conversation.  This is an opportunity for you to learn what unmet needs your potential client might have, what obstacles might come about within the supply chain of your final product and any other information that might help you in the final stages of development.</p>
<p>People typically hate sales calls, but love to talk about their work, so when contacting someone for customer research make it clear that you are not trying to sell them anything, you are interested in learning more about their work and what challenges they face</p>
<p>If the need for your product does not surface when talking about challenges, gently steer the conversation in that direction.  Once the need is clear, ask if a product like yours might solve their problem. Listen more than talk and be open to new ideas.  Honestly assessing potential customer feedback will only help you refine your idea and avoid costly mistakes.</p>
<p>Toward the end of each conversation ask if there is anyone the person knows who you can contact for a similar conversation and if you can use the person’s name as a referral.  Interview as many potential customers as you can to get a diversity of inputs.  You will always learn something from talking to a potential customer no matter how many you have spoken with and you may find you really enjoy it and make some great contacts.</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://davekuhar.github.io/bbic/2017/04/24/tips-tricks-customer-research-basics/">Tips &#038; Tricks: Customer Research Basics</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://davekuhar.github.io/bbic/">Boston Biomedical Innovation Center</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Tips &#038; Tricks: When Searching for Market Information</title>
		<link>https://davekuhar.github.io/bbic/2017/04/03/tips-tricks-searching-market-information/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[B-BIC]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Mon, 03 Apr 2017 14:01:15 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Tips & Tricks]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Tips]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Tricks]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://b-bic.org/?p=784</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>It is always important to know your competitors and how your product compares to theirs, but did you know competitors’ websites can also provide information on reimbursement and market size.  Companies often provide a reimbursement guide for their customers and a company’s annual report frequent has market size and market share data. When searching for&#8230;</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://davekuhar.github.io/bbic/2017/04/03/tips-tricks-searching-market-information/">Tips &#038; Tricks: When Searching for Market Information</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://davekuhar.github.io/bbic/">Boston Biomedical Innovation Center</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<ul>
<li>It is always important to know your competitors and how your product compares to theirs, but did you know competitors’ websites can also provide information on reimbursement and market size.  Companies often provide a reimbursement guide for their customers and a company’s annual report frequent has market size and market share data.</li>
</ul>
<ul>
<li>When searching for market information, put “pdf” or “ppt” after your key words.  This approach will focus the results on PDF files and PowerPoint presentations, which are frequently more relevant and detailed. Also you can use the “-word” function to eliminate those pesky non-relevant results that keep showing up.</li>
</ul>
<ul>
<li>Another great way to find market information is to do an image search rather than a general web search.  You will frequently find relevant graphs, bar charts, pie charts, and tables.  Follow the link of the image source to see if more information is available.</li>
</ul>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://davekuhar.github.io/bbic/2017/04/03/tips-tricks-searching-market-information/">Tips &#038; Tricks: When Searching for Market Information</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://davekuhar.github.io/bbic/">Boston Biomedical Innovation Center</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>FAST PITCH FOR FUNDING: Quick Tips for a successful pitch</title>
		<link>https://davekuhar.github.io/bbic/2017/03/13/fast-pitch-funding-quick-tips-successful-pitch/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[B-BIC]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Mon, 13 Mar 2017 19:21:24 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Tips & Tricks]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[FAST PITCH]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[fast pitch for funding]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://b-bic.org/?p=753</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Keep pitch short and focused on the technology and its commercial application. Limit the discussion of preliminary results, and focus on the most relevant results with conclusions &#8211; not data. Present the science within the context of the business strategy. Keep details to a minimum and use visuals without words when possible. FAST PITCH FOR FUNDING is April 27th at 10:00am.&#8230;</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://davekuhar.github.io/bbic/2017/03/13/fast-pitch-funding-quick-tips-successful-pitch/">FAST PITCH FOR FUNDING: Quick Tips for a successful pitch</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://davekuhar.github.io/bbic/">Boston Biomedical Innovation Center</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<div class="m_8149818489183255676gl-contains-text"></div>
<div class="m_8149818489183255676gl-contains-text">
<table border="0" width="100%" cellspacing="0" cellpadding="0">
<tbody>
<tr>
<td class="m_8149818489183255676editor-text" align="left" valign="top">
<div></div>
<div>
<ul>
<li>Keep pitch short and focused on the technology and its commercial application.</li>
<li>Limit the discussion of preliminary results, and focus on the most relevant results with conclusions &#8211; not data.</li>
<li>Present the science within the context of the business strategy.</li>
<li>Keep details to a minimum and use visuals without words when possible.</li>
</ul>
</div>
<p><b><i>FAST PITCH FOR FUNDING</i></b><i> is April 27th at 10:00am.  This event provides you the opportunity to pitch a team of experts on your research. You will receive immediate feedback with the opportunity to apply for our </i><a href="https://b-bic.org/funding/"><i>grant programs</i></a><i> which can provide up to $350,000 per project, business coaching, and project management.</i></p>
<p><strong><a href="https://www.eventbrite.com/e/fast-pitch-for-funding-tickets-32588335589">REGISTER HERE</a></strong></td>
</tr>
</tbody>
</table>
</div>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://davekuhar.github.io/bbic/2017/03/13/fast-pitch-funding-quick-tips-successful-pitch/">FAST PITCH FOR FUNDING: Quick Tips for a successful pitch</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://davekuhar.github.io/bbic/">Boston Biomedical Innovation Center</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
