<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	>

<channel>
	<title>B-BIC &#8211; Boston Biomedical Innovation Center</title>
	<atom:link href="https://bbic.muellerarchive.com/author/bbic/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>https://bbic.muellerarchive.com/</link>
	<description></description>
	<lastBuildDate>Mon, 26 Jun 2017 13:48:56 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>
	hourly	</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>
	1	</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>https://wordpress.org/?v=5.8.1</generator>

<image>
	<url>https://bbic.muellerarchive.com/wp-content/uploads/2016/11/cropped-bbic-favicon-32x32.png</url>
	<title>B-BIC &#8211; Boston Biomedical Innovation Center</title>
	<link>https://bbic.muellerarchive.com/</link>
	<width>32</width>
	<height>32</height>
</image> 
	<item>
		<title>Testimonial: Resolving Hurdles</title>
		<link>https://bbic.muellerarchive.com/2016/10/27/resolving-hurdles/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[B-BIC]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 27 Oct 2016 21:26:54 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[PI Testimonial]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://b-bic.org/?p=433</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>The B-BIC program has been instrumental in helping us accelerate development of our bioreactor and achieve commercial proof of feasibility that would not have been possible within the same time frame by traditional non-dilutive funding mechanisms available at the time. B-BIC also allowed us to bridge academic and commercial requirements and resolve many practical hurdles&#8230;</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://bbic.muellerarchive.com/2016/10/27/resolving-hurdles/">Testimonial: Resolving Hurdles</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://bbic.muellerarchive.com/">Boston Biomedical Innovation Center</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>The B-BIC program has been instrumental in helping us accelerate development of our bioreactor and achieve commercial proof of feasibility that would not have been possible within the same time frame by traditional non-dilutive funding mechanisms available at the time. B-BIC also allowed us to bridge academic and commercial requirements and resolve many practical hurdles to facilitate the spin out of private company from an academic lab.</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://bbic.muellerarchive.com/2016/10/27/resolving-hurdles/">Testimonial: Resolving Hurdles</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://bbic.muellerarchive.com/">Boston Biomedical Innovation Center</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Testimonial: Challenging Interaction a Huge Plus</title>
		<link>https://bbic.muellerarchive.com/2016/10/27/challenging-interaction-a-huge-plus/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[B-BIC]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 27 Oct 2016 21:25:37 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[PI Testimonial]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://b-bic.org/?p=432</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Here is how B-BIC has helped this project. The money itself. It would be very difficult to raise money for this project from standard sources. Challenging questions from the reviewers. During the review of our preproposal, one challenge from the B-BIC point of contact was that we should design a Phase 3 trial for our&#8230;</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://bbic.muellerarchive.com/2016/10/27/challenging-interaction-a-huge-plus/">Testimonial: Challenging Interaction a Huge Plus</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://bbic.muellerarchive.com/">Boston Biomedical Innovation Center</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Here is how B-BIC has helped this project.</p>
<ol>
<li>The money itself. It would be very difficult to raise money for this project from standard sources.</li>
<li>Challenging questions from the reviewers. During the review of our preproposal, one challenge from the B-BIC point of contact was that we should design a Phase 3 trial for our product and see whether, with a reasonable number of patients, we could generate the statistical power needed to prove our product was superior to current EPO products. This is a very commercially focused question that an academic reviewer would never ask. It took us a long time to get the answer. However, it came in very handy in a recent investor pitch, in which an outside expert (who had run EPO clinical trials) asked me the same question and I was immediately able to answer it.</li>
<li>Back-and-forth with the reviewers, being able to respond to their comments. Doing this has also helped us understand the kind of questions that investors ask, and have ready answers. Also, clinician reviewers had a completely different take on our science than we did. We needed to significantly adapt our story to reach both of these audiences.</li>
<li>Evaluation based driven by the commercial opportunity</li>
</ol>
<p>To sum up, the challenging back-and-forth interaction with B-BIC people has been a huge plus. It has helped us prepare for investor meetings, and also helped us bridge the gap between our own reductionistic protein engineering worldview and that of clinicians.</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://bbic.muellerarchive.com/2016/10/27/challenging-interaction-a-huge-plus/">Testimonial: Challenging Interaction a Huge Plus</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://bbic.muellerarchive.com/">Boston Biomedical Innovation Center</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Testimonial: Clear Objectives</title>
		<link>https://bbic.muellerarchive.com/2016/10/27/clear-objectives/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[B-BIC]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 27 Oct 2016 21:24:14 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[PI Testimonial]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://b-bic.org/?p=431</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>B-BIC has been a communicative and supportive organization to work with and the program is well designed. B-BIC has chosen targeted topics and emphasized commercial translation, making the program objectives clear. This aids the proposer in assessing likelihood of winning an award. The involvement of the program managers has been helpful and informative. The proposal&#8230;</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://bbic.muellerarchive.com/2016/10/27/clear-objectives/">Testimonial: Clear Objectives</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://bbic.muellerarchive.com/">Boston Biomedical Innovation Center</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>B-BIC has been a communicative and supportive organization to work with and the program is well designed. B-BIC has chosen targeted topics and emphasized commercial translation, making the program objectives clear. This aids the proposer in assessing likelihood of winning an award. The involvement of the program managers has been helpful and informative. The proposal evaluation and feedback prior to award was very thorough and I am grateful for the effort that went into that.</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://bbic.muellerarchive.com/2016/10/27/clear-objectives/">Testimonial: Clear Objectives</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://bbic.muellerarchive.com/">Boston Biomedical Innovation Center</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Testimonial: Business Principles Advanced</title>
		<link>https://bbic.muellerarchive.com/2016/10/27/business-principles-advanced/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[B-BIC]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 27 Oct 2016 21:23:18 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[PI Testimonial]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://b-bic.org/?p=430</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>This grant has enabled me to advance the development of a medical device with a high potential clinical impact. This is consistent with my academic career, which centers on translational imaging research. The B-BIC grant has allowed me to engage with marketing and business advisors to learn more deeply about practical business principles necessary to&#8230;</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://bbic.muellerarchive.com/2016/10/27/business-principles-advanced/">Testimonial: Business Principles Advanced</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://bbic.muellerarchive.com/">Boston Biomedical Innovation Center</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>This grant has enabled me to advance the development of a medical device with a high potential clinical impact. This is consistent with my academic career, which centers on translational imaging research. The B-BIC grant has allowed me to engage with marketing and business advisors to learn more deeply about practical business principles necessary to navigate our device towards FDA approval and clinical use.</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://bbic.muellerarchive.com/2016/10/27/business-principles-advanced/">Testimonial: Business Principles Advanced</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://bbic.muellerarchive.com/">Boston Biomedical Innovation Center</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Testimonial: Broadened Horizons</title>
		<link>https://bbic.muellerarchive.com/2016/10/27/broadened-horizons/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[B-BIC]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 27 Oct 2016 21:13:39 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[PI Testimonial]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://b-bic.org/?p=429</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>This project has advanced my professional development objectives by allowing me to learn much about the technology development and commercialization process. Beyond my conventional academic pursuits, involvement with the B-BIC program has broadened my horizons and underlined the importance of translating promising science from our laboratories towards practical/commercial applications. This work has enhanced my interest&#8230;</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://bbic.muellerarchive.com/2016/10/27/broadened-horizons/">Testimonial: Broadened Horizons</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://bbic.muellerarchive.com/">Boston Biomedical Innovation Center</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>This project has advanced my professional development objectives by allowing me to learn much about the technology development and commercialization process. Beyond my conventional academic pursuits, involvement with the B-BIC program has broadened my horizons and underlined the importance of translating promising science from our laboratories towards practical/commercial applications. This work has enhanced my interest in continuing to pursue these lines of efforts, enabling our science to impact society.</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://bbic.muellerarchive.com/2016/10/27/broadened-horizons/">Testimonial: Broadened Horizons</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://bbic.muellerarchive.com/">Boston Biomedical Innovation Center</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Testimonial: Increased Visibility</title>
		<link>https://bbic.muellerarchive.com/2016/10/27/increased-visibility/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[B-BIC]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 27 Oct 2016 21:12:49 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[PI Testimonial]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://b-bic.org/?p=428</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Progress made under this award has increased my visibility to pharmaceutical companies so that I have been sought as an investigator for several companies.</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://bbic.muellerarchive.com/2016/10/27/increased-visibility/">Testimonial: Increased Visibility</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://bbic.muellerarchive.com/">Boston Biomedical Innovation Center</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Progress made under this award has increased my visibility to pharmaceutical companies so that I have been sought as an investigator for several companies.</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://bbic.muellerarchive.com/2016/10/27/increased-visibility/">Testimonial: Increased Visibility</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://bbic.muellerarchive.com/">Boston Biomedical Innovation Center</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Testimonial: Program Invaluable</title>
		<link>https://bbic.muellerarchive.com/2016/10/27/program-invaluable/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[B-BIC]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 27 Oct 2016 21:03:47 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[PI Testimonial]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://b-bic.org/?p=427</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>The B-BIC program has been invaluable in two ways. First, the grant support has allowed us to bring our device from early prototyping stage to full preclinical testing and now at a point where we can focus on achieving FDA clearance for clinical use. Second, the support of advisors have taught me to navigate the&#8230;</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://bbic.muellerarchive.com/2016/10/27/program-invaluable/">Testimonial: Program Invaluable</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://bbic.muellerarchive.com/">Boston Biomedical Innovation Center</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>The B-BIC program has been invaluable in two ways. First, the grant support has allowed us to bring our device from early prototyping stage to full preclinical testing and now at a point where we can focus on achieving FDA clearance for clinical use. Second, the support of advisors have taught me to navigate the various stages of device development from a practical business development perspective, which I now understand to be as critical as scientific proof-of-concept in transitioning any device from benchtop research towards bedside application.</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://bbic.muellerarchive.com/2016/10/27/program-invaluable/">Testimonial: Program Invaluable</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://bbic.muellerarchive.com/">Boston Biomedical Innovation Center</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Platelet BioGenesis</title>
		<link>https://bbic.muellerarchive.com/2016/09/13/platelet-biogenesis/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[B-BIC]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 13 Sep 2016 23:33:17 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[News]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://b-bic.org/?p=132</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Platelet BioGenesis, a biotech startup developing a method for producing life-saving platelets without the need for human donations, is proud to announce that they won second place in the national BioSciKin/Simcere Sino-U.S. Startup Competition in Life Science in Shanghai, China. Platelet BioGenesis was invited to participate in the 2016 national competition following their first place&#8230;</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://bbic.muellerarchive.com/2016/09/13/platelet-biogenesis/">Platelet BioGenesis</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://bbic.muellerarchive.com/">Boston Biomedical Innovation Center</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Platelet BioGenesis, a biotech startup developing a method for producing life-saving platelets without the need for human donations, is proud to announce that they won second place in the national BioSciKin/Simcere Sino-U.S. Startup Competition in Life Science in Shanghai, China.</p>
<p>Platelet BioGenesis was invited to participate in the 2016 national competition following their first place finish in Boston earlier this year. They joined 3 other North American companies (1 from Canada and 2 from California) to compete alongside 8 other finalists from China. The conference spanned 3 days and, amongst many strong competitors, Platelet BioGenesis placed 2nd and received a cash prize.</p>
<p>“We are very proud to have done so well amongst so many strong competitors,” said Sven Karlsson, President of Platelet BioGenesis. “Our endeavor has generated a lot of interest in the sector. We are tackling a very ambitious challenge that will extend access to platelet transfusions to billions of people &#8211; it’s exciting to be recognized for that mission.”</p>
<p>“China is investing heavily in a strong biotechnology sector and it was incredible to see this growth first hand.” said Dr. Jonathan Thon, Assistant Professor at Brigham and Women’s Hospital and Harvard Medical School, and inventor of Platelet BioGenesis’ patented bioreactor. “Regenerative medicine is the future of healthcare, we’re proud to be leading the way.”</p>
<h3>About Platelet BioGenesis</h3>
<p>Platelet BioGenesis is a pre-clinical stage biotech company that was spun out of Harvard in 2014 to produce donor-independent human platelets from pluripotent stem cells Platelet BioGenesis has developed and patented a microfluidic bioreactor, and shown that functional platelets can be generated from human stem cell cultures at scale. The company was selected to participate in MassCONNECT (run by MassBio), was a 2014 MassChallenge Finalist, a 2016 BioSciKin business competition winner, and has received support from the Massachusetts Life Sciences Center, and the NIH.</p>
<p><a href="http://www.plateletbiogenesis.com/">www.plateletbiogenesis.com</a> | twitter <a href="https://twitter.com/PlateletBioGen">@plateletbiogen</a></p>
<h3>About Simcere</h3>
<p>Simcere is an emerging leader in developing, manufacturing and marketing of innovative medicines and branded generics in China. Simcere was the first Chinese chemical and biological drug company to list on the NYSE in 2007. In 2013, the company went private for strategic considerations. In 2015, Simcere’s translational medicine and innovative drug R&amp;D platform was recognized as a State Key Laboratory by the National Ministry of Science and Technology. The company has been actively pursuing cross-border partnerships to bring global innovation to China. In Boston and New Jersey, Simcere now has two offices in the US for accelerating international business development.</p>
<h3>About BioSciKin</h3>
<p>BioSciKin (BSK) is an open platform in China for life science entrepreneurs and innovators. BSK focuses on three major healthcare areas: novel therapeutics, medical devices and mobile healthcare services, BSK is looking for partnership from all over the world for co-development of innovative approaches in precision medicine. In Nanjing, Shanghai and Tianjin, BSK has established 3 R&amp;D-oriented incubation parks with advanced R&amp;D facilities to provide entrepreneurs with customized service and support packages. For more information, please go to BSK’s official website: www.bioscikin.com</p>
<p>Contact: Platelet BioGenesis, Whitney Berry, <a href="tel:7205099448">(720) 509.9448</a> | wberry@plateletbiogenesis.com</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://bbic.muellerarchive.com/2016/09/13/platelet-biogenesis/">Platelet BioGenesis</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://bbic.muellerarchive.com/">Boston Biomedical Innovation Center</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>The Skills Development Center</title>
		<link>https://bbic.muellerarchive.com/2016/09/02/the-skills-development-center/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[B-BIC]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 02 Sep 2016 23:31:50 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[News]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://b-bic.org/?p=131</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>The Boston Biomedical Innovation Center (B-BIC) Skills Development Center (SDC) offers workshops focused on Leadership, Management, and Entrepreneurship. Researchers know how to develop groundbreaking new technologies.  However, to bring new technologies into the public arena where they can affect human health, researchers must also be able to navigate the path to commercialization, a process demanding&#8230;</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://bbic.muellerarchive.com/2016/09/02/the-skills-development-center/">The Skills Development Center</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://bbic.muellerarchive.com/">Boston Biomedical Innovation Center</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>The Boston Biomedical Innovation Center (B-BIC) Skills Development Center (SDC) offers workshops focused on Leadership, Management, and Entrepreneurship.</p>
<p>Researchers know how to develop groundbreaking new technologies.  However, to bring new technologies into the public arena where they can affect human health, researchers must also be able to navigate the path to commercialization, a process demanding a broader set of business, finance, and entrepreneurial skills.</p>
<p>The Skills Development Center offers open access online learning resources and customized services designed to promote academic technology commercialization efforts within B-BIC organizations and all Harvard-affiliated institutions.  The SDC is a partnership between Boston Biomedical Innovation Center and Harvard Catalyst | The Harvard Clinical and Translational Science Center.</p>
<p>Event details can be found at SDC Eventbrite for events scheduled in October and registration is currently open.</p>
<p>10/4/16  Finding the Market for Your Product &#8211; located at Beth Israel Deaconess Medical Center<br />
10/17/16    Leading Scientific Teams – located at Simmons College<br />
10/17/16    Setting Goals and Giving Feedback – located at Simmons College<br />
10/19/16    Presentation Coaching – located at Massachusetts General Hospital<br />
10/24/16    Negotiation and Conflict Resolution for Scientists – located at Boston University<br />
11/1/16    Launching Successful Products: A Roadmap for Accelerated Product Development – located at Brigham and Women’s Hospital<br />
11/2/16   Presentation Coaching – located at Boston Children’s Hospital</p>
<p>Contact: Elizabeth Hale | <a href="tel:617-521-2027">617-521-2027</a> | <a href="mailto:emhale@partners.org">emhale@partners.org</a></p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://bbic.muellerarchive.com/2016/09/02/the-skills-development-center/">The Skills Development Center</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://bbic.muellerarchive.com/">Boston Biomedical Innovation Center</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>NEW AWARDS: B-BIC selects five new technologies to award support for commercial development</title>
		<link>https://bbic.muellerarchive.com/2016/07/07/b-bic-selects-five-new-technologies-to-award-support-for-commercial-development/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[B-BIC]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 07 Jul 2016 23:31:43 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[New Award]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[News]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Bruce Bean]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Elazer Edelman]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Eric Gale]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[HARVARD MEDICAL SCHOOL]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Jonghan Kim]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Massachusetts General Hospital]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Massachusetts Institute of Technology]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Northeastern University]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Pamela Silver]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://b-bic.org/?p=130</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>RECIPIENT:  Dr. Pamela Silver TITLE: A Targeted Erythropoietin-Based Therapeutic TYPE OF AWARD:  DRIVE INSTITUTION: Harvard Medical School DESCRIPTION:  Pamela Silver, PhD., Elliot T and Onie H Adams Professor of Biochemistry and Systems Biology, Harvard Medical School, and a founding member of the Wyss Institute was awarded a DRIVE grant for continued development of a targeted erythropoietin-based therapeutic.  EPO plays&#8230;</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://bbic.muellerarchive.com/2016/07/07/b-bic-selects-five-new-technologies-to-award-support-for-commercial-development/">NEW AWARDS: B-BIC selects five new technologies to award support for commercial development</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://bbic.muellerarchive.com/">Boston Biomedical Innovation Center</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<div><strong>RECIPIENT</strong>:  Dr. Pamela Silver<b></b></div>
<div>
<div><strong>TITLE</strong>: A Targeted Erythropoietin-Based Therapeutic</div>
<div><strong>TYPE OF AWARD:</strong>  DRIVE</div>
<div><strong>INSTITUTION</strong>: Harvard Medical School</div>
<div><strong>DESCRIPTION</strong>:  Pamela Silver, PhD., Elliot T and Onie H Adams Professor of Biochemistry and Systems Biology, Harvard Medical School, and a founding member of the Wyss Institute was awarded a DRIVE grant for continued development of a targeted erythropoietin-based therapeutic.  EPO plays multiple biological roles by binding to EPO receptors (EPO-R) on diverse cell types, including erythroid progenitors, macrophages, pro-megakaryocytes, cancer cells, and neurons. The therapeutic goal of this work is to minimize the side effects of EPO by targeting this protein to red blood cell (RBC) precursors and away from other cell types. Recombinant EPO has been used for two decades to treat forms of anemia associated with end-stage renal failure, AIDS, chemotherapy, or hemoglobinopathies. Clinical use of EPO has recently decreased due to concerns over the drug’s off-target effects: EPO treatment has been linked to tumor recurrence and platelet formation or activation, which may lead to coronary disease or thrombosis. Targeting EPO to RBC precursors should allow higher doses to fully restore RBC levels without increasing the risk of cardiovascular events or cancer progression. In addition, the targeted EPO developed here should have an extended serum half-life and reduced immunogenicity relative to existing EPO drugs.</div>
</div>
<div></div>
<div><strong>RECIPIENT</strong>:  Dr. Jonghan Kim<b></b></div>
<div>
<div><strong>TITLE</strong>: Pharmacokinetics of Multifunctional Nanochelators In Iron Overload Disorders</div>
<div><strong>TYPE OF AWARD:</strong>  PILOT</div>
<div><strong>INSTITUTION</strong>: Northeastern University</div>
<div><strong>DESCRIPTION</strong>:  Jonghan Kim, PhD, Assistant Professor of Pharmaceutical Sciences at Northeastern University was awarded a Pilot grant for development of the pharmacokinetics of multifunctional nanochelators in iron overload disorders.  Increased iron stores are associated with well-established risk factors of heart and liver failure, arthritis, dyslipidemia and diabetes. Iron overload occurs in several anemias and in addition, hereditary hemochromatosis, a genetic iron overload disorder, affects 7-32% of North American populations with genetic variants. Several neurodegenerative diseases (e.g. Alzheimer’s and Parkinson’s diseases) are also associated with high iron stores in the brain. Although chelation therapy has been widely used to improve disease conditions in patients with iron overload, iron chelators have serious adverse effects, including hypotension, tachycardia, agranulocytosis, neutropenia, neurotoxicity, musculoskeletal-joint pains, gastrointestinal disturbances and even death. This work will develop ultrasmall nanoprobes that covalently bind iron chelators (“nanochelators”) and thus limit drug distribution into non-target tissues, while efficiently capturing plasma iron and being exclusively cleared via urine, thereby decreasing iron burden and reducing the risk of iron-induced tissue damage, including heart diseases and dyslipidemia.</div>
</div>
<div></div>
<div></div>
<div><strong>RECIPIENT</strong>:  Dr. Eric Gale<b></b></div>
<div>
<div><strong>TITLE</strong>: A Manganese Alternative To Gadolinium For MRI Contrast</div>
<div><strong>TYPE OF AWARD:</strong>  DRIVE</div>
<div><strong>INSTITUTION</strong>: Massachusetts General Hospital</div>
<div><strong>DESCRIPTION</strong>:  Eric Gale, PhD, Massachusetts General Hospital Martinos Center for Biomedical Engineering received a DRIVE grant to develop a manganese alternative to gadolinium for MRI contrast.  Gadolinium based contrast agents (GBCAs) are routinely administered to visualize vascular and tissue irregularities using MRI but concerns over GBCA toxicity in patients suffering kidney disease have emerged over the last decade. In 2007 the FDA labeled all GBCAs with a black box warning.  GBCA sales dropped by 1 million vials (~10%) in the year following the FDA issued warnings. This decrease reflects contrast withheld from patients suffering moderate-to-advanced chronic kidney disease which is 8% of the US population. No replacement technology has emerged and CKD patients are continuously denied contrast enhanced examinations. This non-gadolinium containing contrast agent is designed to be compatible with renally insufficient patients and operates analogously to the standard of care but with an improved toxicity and clearance profile. The primary indication for the product will be MR angiography, but it is amenable to any applications requiring GBCAs.</div>
</div>
<div></div>
<div><strong>RECIPIENT</strong>:  Dr. Elazer Edelman<b></b></div>
<div>
<div><strong>TITLE</strong>:  A minimally invasive tissue engineering therapies for acute airway injuries.</div>
<div><strong>TYPE OF AWARD:</strong>  PILOT</div>
<div><strong>INSTITUTION</strong>: Massachusetts Institute of Technology</div>
<div><strong>DESCRIPTION</strong>:  Elazer Edelman, MD, Thomas D. and Virginia W. Cabot Professor of Health Sciences and Technology, Massachusetts Institute of Technology, Professor of Medicine, Harvard Medical School, and Senior Attending Physician, Brigham and Women’s Hospital receives a DRIVE award to develop minimally invasive tissue engineering therapies for acute airway injuries. Airway inhalation injury produces severe lung damage and respiratory failure, and is the most common cause of death in burn centers. By embedding healthy bronchial epithelial and endothelial cells within porous matrices, the team has created stable cell constructs which can be implanted into peri-tracheal soft tissue surrounding injury sites. The matrix micro-environment allows for cell preservation with significant shelf-life, ready transport, and an effective therapeutic unit with no demonstrable immune response. Acellularized gelatin particle formulation also has been developed which can be deployed as an injectable, expandable gel around sites of injury. With the DRIVE award, the team will optimize the technology and begin large animal pilot studies on injectable formulations. Ultimately, Dr Edelman envisions two minimally invasive clinical formulations in treating inhalation injuries; an implantable cellularized matrix and injectable matrix particles in an expandable gel. The latter can be injected around the site of injury by first responders while the former can be deployed at designated medical centers as definitive therapy for inhalation injury.</div>
</div>
<div></div>
<div></div>
<div><strong>RECIPIENT</strong>:  Dr. Bruce Bean<b></b></div>
<div>
<div><strong>TITLE</strong>: Silencing airway nociceptors for treatment of cough and airway inflammation</div>
<div><strong>TYPE OF AWARD:</strong>  PILOT</div>
<div><strong>INSTITUTION</strong>: Harvard Medical School</div>
<div><strong>DESCRIPTION:  </strong>Bruce Bean, PhD, Professor of Neurobiology, Harvard Medical School receives a DRIVE award for silencing airway nociceptors for treatment of cough and airway inflammation. Cough is the most common reason patients see their primary care physician and the sixth most common reason for hospital-based outpatient care. Cough is poorly treated by currently available therapeutics, including opioids, dextromethorphan and benzonatate. The team has developed a novel treatment based on selective delivery of permanently charged cationic sodium channel blockers into activated airway nociceptors through activated TRPV1 and TRPA1 ion channels, which are selectively expressed by nociceptors. Using the tool compound delivered as an inhaled aerosol, the team has shown that this approach can inhibit cough and dramatically reducing airway inflammation in small animal models.  They have now synthesized novel compounds that block neuronal sodium channels more potently and propose to test these and initiate pharmacokinetic studies.</div>
</div>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://bbic.muellerarchive.com/2016/07/07/b-bic-selects-five-new-technologies-to-award-support-for-commercial-development/">NEW AWARDS: B-BIC selects five new technologies to award support for commercial development</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://bbic.muellerarchive.com/">Boston Biomedical Innovation Center</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
