<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	>

<channel>
	<title>B-BIC &#8211; Boston Biomedical Innovation Center</title>
	<atom:link href="https://davekuhar.github.io/bbic/author/communications/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>https://davekuhar.github.io/bbic/</link>
	<description></description>
	<lastBuildDate>Mon, 23 Mar 2020 15:51:05 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>
	hourly	</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>
	1	</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>https://wordpress.org/?v=5.8.1</generator>

<image>
	<url>https://davekuhar.github.io/bbic/wp-content/uploads/2016/11/cropped-bbic-favicon-32x32.png</url>
	<title>B-BIC &#8211; Boston Biomedical Innovation Center</title>
	<link>https://davekuhar.github.io/bbic/</link>
	<width>32</width>
	<height>32</height>
</image> 
	<item>
		<title>New Award:  Congratulations Dr. Aaron Grant!!</title>
		<link>https://davekuhar.github.io/bbic/2020/02/11/new-award-congratulations-dr-aaron-grant/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[B-BIC]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 11 Feb 2020 18:46:59 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[New Award]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://b-bic.org/?p=1301</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>TITLE: Technology for Functional and Metabolic Imaging with Hyperpolarized MRI TYPE OF AWARD: Pilot CLINICAL AREA:  Heart INSTITUTION:  Beth Israel Deaconess Medical Center DESCRIPTION: MRI provides a wealth of anatomical information, but its ability to assess functional parameters such as blood flow (perfusion) and metabolism is limited by its low sensitivity and the limited range of available contrast&#8230;</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://davekuhar.github.io/bbic/2020/02/11/new-award-congratulations-dr-aaron-grant/">New Award:  Congratulations Dr. Aaron Grant!!</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://davekuhar.github.io/bbic/">Boston Biomedical Innovation Center</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<div><strong>TITLE</strong>: Technology for Functional and Metabolic Imaging with Hyperpolarized MRI</div>
<div><strong>TYPE OF AWARD:</strong> Pilot</div>
<div><strong>CLINICAL AREA: </strong> Heart</div>
<div><strong>INSTITUTION: </strong> Beth Israel Deaconess Medical Center</div>
<div></div>
<div><strong>DESCRIPTION:</strong> MRI provides a wealth of anatomical information, but its ability to assess functional parameters such as blood flow (perfusion) and metabolism is limited by its low sensitivity and the limited range of available contrast agents. This limitation negatively impacts virtually every clinical scenario where contrast- enhanced imaging plays a role, including cancer, heart disease, and stroke, to name a few. In the work proposed here, we hope to build the basis for a new approach to diagnostic imaging based on a technology known as hyperpolarized carbon-13 MRI. In hyperpolarized MRI, a tracer molecule is prepared exogenously in a state of dramatically enhanced nuclear magnetization and administered intravenously, enabling real-time imaging of the transport, uptake, and metabolism the tracer. Molecules including glucose, glutamine, and pyruvate can be imaged with this technology. Applications to heart disease, lung, cancer, diabetes, and inflammation have been demonstrated pre-clinically, and clinical trials in heart disease and cancer are underway.  Widespread adoption of hyperpolarization technology has been hampered by the complexity, poor reliability and high cost of existing instruments for preparing hyperpolarized agents. Here we propose to develop alternative technology for hyperpolarization based on simple, inexpensive hardware that employs a method known as parahydrogen-induced polarization (PHIP). As a first step toward development of this technology, in this Pilot application we propose to develop and test a novel myocardial perfusion imaging agent that is tailored for use with parahydrogen-based hyperpolarizers.</div>
<div></div>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://davekuhar.github.io/bbic/2020/02/11/new-award-congratulations-dr-aaron-grant/">New Award:  Congratulations Dr. Aaron Grant!!</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://davekuhar.github.io/bbic/">Boston Biomedical Innovation Center</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Specialist Series: How To Identify The Right Inflection Points</title>
		<link>https://davekuhar.github.io/bbic/2020/02/11/how-to-identify-the-right-inflection-points/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[B-BIC]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 11 Feb 2020 18:32:21 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Specialist Series]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Specialist Article]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[specialist series]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://b-bic.org/?p=1299</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Contributed by Erin McKenna, Deputy Director of B-BIC &#38; Paul Tessier, B-BIC Coach Once you understand the unmet clinical need your technology can address and have connected that need with a solid business opportunity, the next thing to be considered is to understand the development path for the product you want to create. Outlining the&#8230;</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://davekuhar.github.io/bbic/2020/02/11/how-to-identify-the-right-inflection-points/">Specialist Series: How To Identify The Right Inflection Points</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://davekuhar.github.io/bbic/">Boston Biomedical Innovation Center</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><em>Contributed by Erin McKenna, Deputy Director of B-BIC &amp; Paul Tessier, B-BIC Coach</em></p>
<p>Once you understand the unmet clinical need your technology can address and have connected that need with a solid business opportunity, the next thing to be considered is to understand the development path for the product you want to create. Outlining the potential path (or likely paths) forward is a necessary step for attracting funding, whether it be through grants or investors. Anyone interested in contributing resources towards developing your concept into a product will want to understand two general things. The first is understanding the resource requirements for developing your product and bringing it to the market. Second is outlining the critical steps along the way where you can gauge that you have reduced the most significant risks and that the development work will lead to a successful product. Those points are typically referred to as inflection points or milestones, and grant reviewers and savvy investors will want to know what they are and agree that they are the correct ones before they invest in developing your technology.</p>
<p>In many cases, inflection points can be true for several different types of technologies. Some common ones include:</p>
<ul>
<li>Technology development milestones including lead compound identification, or functional prototype development</li>
<li>Pre-clinical testing milestones such as pharmacokinetics study completion, toxicity studies, or completion of efficacy studies in animals (where that is possible)</li>
<li>Intellectual property milestones such as obtaining a license to patents and/or filing your patents</li>
<li>Clinical milestones such as approval of an Investigational New Drug (IND) or Investigational Device Exemption (IDE), and the completion of key clinical studies such as Phase 1, 2, and 3 studies for pharmaceuticals and biologics or safety and pivotal studies for devices</li>
<li>Regulatory milestones such as submission or acceptance of a pre-market submission, for instance, a New Drug Application (NDA) for pharmaceuticals and biologics or Pre-Market Approval (PMA) or 510k clearance for devices</li>
<li>Making the product available commercially for use, often referred to as the product launch</li>
</ul>
<p>However, assembling a plan for developing your technology must be customized to fit the needs of the product you want to develop. So, in addition to carefully understanding which of the above milestones are the most important for your product, you also need to determine where the biggest risks are for failure along the development pathway. Potential funders will be assessing risks in a range of areas, including technology, regulatory, market/business, and clinical. You can learn what the biggest risks are by gathering input from clinical users and from experts in the technology, in the market space your product will enter, in regulatory and reimbursement strategy, in market analysis, and from potential investors. The key to having productive discussions that will help you identify the most impactful inflection points will be to ask questions about the ways the development of your product could fail, and which of those ways has the highest likelihood of occurring. These things will lead you to understand the work you will need to do to convince others, especially investors, that the product you are asking for support in developing can succeed.</p>
<p>Your development plan should be broken down into phases, each phase having milestones that further reduce risks. Potential funders will want to know what their investment will be used to accomplish and how accomplishing those goals will create the next inflection point allowing you to obtain the next round of funding. The goal is to create inflection points that show both significant risk reduction and progress toward commercialization. Balancing these can sometimes be challenging. For example, you may hear a concern from potential clinical users or investors that may not be directly connected to the most critical studies needed to gain regulatory approval. To obtain the necessary support from funders, you may need to consider front-loading plans for completing the work required to address their concerns. At B-BIC, we typically work with teams to make sure they understand how potential funders think and use that input to build plans designed to address their most significant concerns as quickly as possible.</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://davekuhar.github.io/bbic/2020/02/11/how-to-identify-the-right-inflection-points/">Specialist Series: How To Identify The Right Inflection Points</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://davekuhar.github.io/bbic/">Boston Biomedical Innovation Center</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>New Award: Congratulations Bradley Maron, MD!</title>
		<link>https://davekuhar.github.io/bbic/2020/01/13/new-award-congratulations-bradley-maron-md/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[B-BIC]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Mon, 13 Jan 2020 17:47:48 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[New Award]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[News]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://b-bic.org/?p=1291</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>TITLE: NEDD9 Monoclonal Antibody Therapeutic for Pulmonary Thromboembolic Disease TYPE OF AWARD: Drive CLINICAL AREA:  Biologic INSTITUTION: Brigham and Women&#8217;s Hospital DESCRIPTION: Increased platelet-endothelial adhesion is a central pathobiological event underlying the pathogenesis of pulmonary arterial hypertension (PAH) and chronic thromboembolic pulmonary hypertension (CTEPH). Current therapies to treat thrombosis in PAH and CTEPH emphasize non-specific coagulation proteins, and are associated&#8230;</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://davekuhar.github.io/bbic/2020/01/13/new-award-congratulations-bradley-maron-md/">New Award: Congratulations Bradley Maron, MD!</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://davekuhar.github.io/bbic/">Boston Biomedical Innovation Center</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<div><strong>TITLE: </strong>NEDD9 Monoclonal Antibody Therapeutic for Pulmonary Thromboembolic Disease</div>
<div><strong>TYPE OF AWARD:</strong> Drive</div>
<div><strong>CLINICAL AREA: </strong> Biologic</div>
<div><strong>INSTITUTION</strong>: Brigham and Women&#8217;s Hospital</div>
<div></div>
<div></div>
<div><strong>DESCRIPTION</strong>: Increased platelet-endothelial adhesion is a central pathobiological event underlying the pathogenesis of pulmonary arterial hypertension (PAH) and chronic thromboembolic pulmonary hypertension (CTEPH). Current therapies to treat thrombosis in PAH and CTEPH emphasize non-specific coagulation proteins, and are associated with elevated rates of off-target effects (e.g., intracranial hemorrhage). Developing a pulmonary vascular-specific drug has several high impact and favorable advantages to current standard of care, but such therapies not exist currently. In this proposal, we present novel data demonstrating that the substrate domain of the protein NEDD9 is a modifiable target to limit thrombosis selectively in the pulmonary circulation. Specifically, our data suggests that NEDD9 on the outward facing plasma membrane is increased by hypoxia selectively in human pulmonary artery endothelial cells, which, in turn, functions as a target of platelet P-selectin to modulate platelet-endothelial interactions in vitro and pulmonary thrombosis in vivo.</div>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p>We propose experiments using PAH and CTEPH animal models and patient samples to profile the therapeutic effect of a novel monoclonal antibody against the pro-thrombotic NEDD9 peptide sequence (mAb-NEDD9). Go/No-go decisions, pivot points and milestone markers are detailed in the accompanying proposal. Overall, results of the proposed experiments aim to i) establish NEDD9 as a druggable site to inhibit thrombosis in PAH and CTEPH, ii) develop a high quality mAb-NEDD9, and iii) demonstrate that the mAb-NEDD9 inhibits platelet adhesion to pulmonary artery endothelial cells in vitro and inhibits thrombosis, vascular remodeling, and pulmonary hypertension in PAH/CTEPH animal models in vivo. Deliverables from this project will be well positioned for early clinical testing.</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://davekuhar.github.io/bbic/2020/01/13/new-award-congratulations-bradley-maron-md/">New Award: Congratulations Bradley Maron, MD!</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://davekuhar.github.io/bbic/">Boston Biomedical Innovation Center</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>New Award:  Congratulations Suneet Agarwal, MD, PhD!</title>
		<link>https://davekuhar.github.io/bbic/2020/01/13/new-award-congratulations-suneet-agarwal-md-phd/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[B-BIC]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Mon, 13 Jan 2020 17:43:34 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[New Award]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://b-bic.org/?p=1288</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>TITLE: Novel Small Molecule Therapeutics for Genetic Lung and Blood Diseases TYPE OF AWARD: Drive CLINICAL AREA:  Small Molecule INSTITUTION: Boston Children&#8217;s Hospital DESCRIPTION: Telomere diseases encompass a spectrum of rare and fatal syndromes that are caused by mutations in genes regulating telomere biology. These include the severe childhood blood disorder dyskeratosis congenita (DC) and later-onset diseases such as&#8230;</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://davekuhar.github.io/bbic/2020/01/13/new-award-congratulations-suneet-agarwal-md-phd/">New Award:  Congratulations Suneet Agarwal, MD, PhD!</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://davekuhar.github.io/bbic/">Boston Biomedical Innovation Center</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<div><strong>TITLE</strong>: Novel Small Molecule Therapeutics for Genetic Lung and Blood Diseases</div>
<div><strong>TYPE OF AWARD:</strong> Drive</div>
<div><strong>CLINICAL AREA:</strong>  Small Molecule</div>
<div><strong>INSTITUTION:</strong> Boston Children&#8217;s Hospital</div>
<div></div>
<div></div>
<div><strong>DESCRIPTION</strong>: Telomere diseases encompass a spectrum of rare and fatal syndromes that are caused by mutations in genes regulating telomere biology. These include the severe childhood blood disorder dyskeratosis congenita (DC) and later-onset diseases such as pulmonary fibrosis (PF). Despite progress in gene and pathway discovery in telomere diseases in the past two decades, there has been no translation of this knowledge into therapies and there are no curative treatments. In our recent work identifying genetic lesions in DC and PF patients, we defined a new pathway regulating telomere maintenance, which we now aim to target for the treatment of DC, PF and other degenerative disorders.</div>
<div></div>
<div></div>
<div>We discovered components of the post-transcriptional machinery that regulate accumulation of the non-coding telomerase RNA (TERC), which is critical for telomerase function and is disrupted in several genetic forms of telomere diseases. We found that inhibiting one of these factors, PAPD5, restores TERC and telomere maintenance in induced pluripotent stem cells (iPSCs) from patients with DC or PF. We have discovered small molecule modulators of this enzyme that we now aim to develop into therapeutics. The goal of this project is to advance a small molecule inhibitor strategy targeting PAPD5 to clinical lead stage. If successful, this strategy will provide a novel approach to manipulate telomerase for the treatment of genetic lung and blood diseases caused by defective telomere maintenance, and potentially other degenerative disorders.</div>
<div></div>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://davekuhar.github.io/bbic/2020/01/13/new-award-congratulations-suneet-agarwal-md-phd/">New Award:  Congratulations Suneet Agarwal, MD, PhD!</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://davekuhar.github.io/bbic/">Boston Biomedical Innovation Center</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Specialist Series: Does Your Great Idea Have A Great Market Opportunity?</title>
		<link>https://davekuhar.github.io/bbic/2020/01/13/does-your-great-idea-have-a-great-market-opportunity/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[B-BIC]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Mon, 13 Jan 2020 17:33:09 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Specialist Series]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[specialist series]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://b-bic.org/?p=1285</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Contributed by Ilsa Webeck B-BIC Skills Development Expert Developing Innovative Strategies for Leading Edge Medical Technology Companies “I have an idea. A great idea. I mean, it’s an “I can’t believe no one has thought of this before” idea. The market for this product is going to be enormous.”  In conversations with innovators spanning devices, biologics,&#8230;</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://davekuhar.github.io/bbic/2020/01/13/does-your-great-idea-have-a-great-market-opportunity/">Specialist Series: Does Your Great Idea Have A Great Market Opportunity?</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://davekuhar.github.io/bbic/">Boston Biomedical Innovation Center</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<div><em>Contributed by Ilsa Webeck</em></div>
<div><em>B-BIC Skills Development Expert</em></div>
<div><em>Developing Innovative Strategies for Leading Edge Medical Technology Companies</em></div>
<p>“I have an idea. A great idea. I mean, it’s an “I can’t believe no one has thought of this before” idea. The market for this product is going to be enormous.”<span class="Apple-converted-space"> </span></p>
<p>In conversations with innovators spanning devices, biologics, diagnostic tools, and many areas in between, I have heard this common refrain more times than I can count.<span class="Apple-converted-space">  </span>These conversations have even included the phrase “it is a billion-dollar market opportunity.” <span class="Apple-converted-space"> </span></p>
<p>While they intend to convey the belief that they have huge market potential and feel very strongly about the direction that they are going, they are, in fact, unintentionally signaling that they haven’t done the real work needed to understand the real opportunity. <span class="Apple-converted-space"> </span></p>
<p>Enthusiasm, excitement, and drive are all essential characteristics for an entrepreneur; however, my role is to temper this eagerness with a good dose of real market intel. All the academic preparation and focused development efforts will only go so far.<span class="Apple-converted-space">  </span>It is necessary to step out of your comfort zone to answer some critical questions about product potential before knowing if that great idea is also a commercially viable one. <span class="Apple-converted-space"> </span></p>
<p>To know the real market opportunity, and therefore revenue potential for a novel healthcare product, a key factor is to know if anyone will pay for it.<span class="Apple-converted-space">  </span>Understanding the reimbursement landscape, economic environment, and purchasing dynamics will get you on your way to understanding the real commercial opportunity.</p>
<ul>
<li><b>Reimbursement Landscape:</b> What are insurance companies and government agencies paying for similar products?<span class="Apple-converted-space">  </span>What are the direct and indirect competitors that could influence the reimbursement structure?<span class="Apple-converted-space">  </span>Will your product cause an increase or decrease in overall costs?<span class="Apple-converted-space">  </span>What are the hard costs (devices, drugs, clinic/bed space etc.) and soft costs (nursing time, improved workflow, good will, etc.) associated with using your product?<span class="Apple-converted-space">  </span><i>Pulling together these costs will give you a better picture of your pricing windows and room for margins and profitability.</i></li>
<li><b>Economic Environment</b>: What is the environment within which you would introduce the product?<span class="Apple-converted-space">  </span>Look to know the space as well as you can.<span class="Apple-converted-space">  </span>For example, is the product used in a particularly difficult type of tumor where doctors are desperate for options and insurance companies are more lenient, or would you be increasing the cost of a screening colonoscopy where margins are already razor thin?<span class="Apple-converted-space">  </span>How does this environment behave when new products are introduced?<span class="Apple-converted-space">  </span>Do they require a high degree of clinical data and peer-reviewed publications or are they willing to try something new with safety data and a few case studies?<span class="Apple-converted-space">  </span><i>The answer to these questions will help you understand the potential challenges to introduce your product in the space.</i></li>
<li><b>Purchasing Dynamics</b>: What are the conditions for hospital/clinic purchasing agents for this type of product?<span class="Apple-converted-space">  </span>Are they under any extra pressure in your area of specialization due to bundled care, close scrutiny, competitive contracts, or other reasons?<span class="Apple-converted-space">  </span>How difficult is it to get another product in your category in front of the right professionals?<span class="Apple-converted-space">  </span>What are the purchasing cycles where your product is used?<span class="Apple-converted-space">  </span><i>Knowing how your product fits into the purchasing dynamics will help you know more about potential adoption.</i></li>
</ul>
<p>Do the research to address these factors and help you better understand the market opportunity and real potential for your new product.<span class="Apple-converted-space"> </span></p>
<p>&#8212;&#8212;&#8212;&#8212;&#8212;&#8212;&#8212;&#8212;&#8212;&#8212;&#8212;&#8212;&#8212;&#8212;&#8212;&#8212;&#8212;-</p>
<p>Ilsa Webeck founded <a href="http://www.medtechstrategiesllc.com/">MedTech Strategies</a>, a boutique, strategic research consulting firm, with the knowledge that all companies, regardless of their size, need to develop a product/service value proposition and understand the business of healthcare in order to be successful. <span class="Apple-converted-space">  </span>She works with companies on new technology initiatives focused on identifying value and actionable outcomes for growth. Her past roles include corporate planning, product management and early product strategy at Johnson &amp; Johnson, Biogen and Health Advances. Ilsa holds a BA in Biology from Dartmouth College and an MBA from the Tuck School of Business.<span class="Apple-converted-space">  </span>She is an invited lecturer at the Boston Biomedical Innovation Center (B-BIC) and is a member of the board for the Medical Development Group (MDG).</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://davekuhar.github.io/bbic/2020/01/13/does-your-great-idea-have-a-great-market-opportunity/">Specialist Series: Does Your Great Idea Have A Great Market Opportunity?</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://davekuhar.github.io/bbic/">Boston Biomedical Innovation Center</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Specialist Series: Unmet Clinical Need</title>
		<link>https://davekuhar.github.io/bbic/2019/11/14/unmet-clinical-need/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[B-BIC]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 14 Nov 2019 13:26:47 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Specialist Series]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[specialist series]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://b-bic.org/?p=1282</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Written by Paul Tessier A common refrain heard by healthcare entrepreneurs is that they should focus on satisfying an “unmet clinical need,” however there is no universal definition of the phrase, “unmet clinical need.”  Even established companies and public healthcare agencies, who use the concept of an unmet clinical need to assist in developing product&#8230;</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://davekuhar.github.io/bbic/2019/11/14/unmet-clinical-need/">Specialist Series: Unmet Clinical Need</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://davekuhar.github.io/bbic/">Boston Biomedical Innovation Center</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Written by Paul Tessier</p>
<p>A common refrain heard by healthcare entrepreneurs is that they should focus on satisfying an “unmet clinical need,” however there is no universal definition of the phrase, “unmet clinical need.”<span class="Apple-converted-space">  </span>Even established companies and public healthcare agencies, who use the concept of an unmet clinical need to assist in developing product roadmaps and healthcare policy, respectively, frequently struggle to gain consensus. The reason is that there are degrees of need, and the perceived importance of a need varies across the many stakeholders in the healthcare ecosystem.</p>
<p>It is generally agreed upon that there are three essential elements to consider in assessing an unmet clinical need; adequacy/availability of treatments, disease severity or burden, and size of the affected population. Related to the adequacy of treatments is the benefit of a newly proposed solution over the current treatment. Payers and value assessment committees are typically not willing to pay for an incremental increase in benefit over the existing standard of care. Diseases with high severity (e.g., morbidity &amp; mortality) and high burden (e.g., frequency &amp; cost of hospitalization) tend to get more attention and are considered more attractive needs to address. Lastly, the size of the affected population typically relates directly to the size of the business opportunity and impact of the product.<span class="Apple-converted-space"> </span></p>
<p>While healthcare entrepreneurs strive to have a positive impact on patient care, achieving that goal is only possible if they are addressing a “business-viable” unmet clinical need. This is where the product addressing the unmet clinical need can result in a profitable product-line or business. Patients, clinicians, and payers may be the target customers for your product. Still, you have other “customers” to satisfy as well – namely granting agencies and investors who will be looking at the business viability of your plan.</p>
<p>Not every unmet clinical need is a business-viable unmet clinical need. However, it is still essential to start your entrepreneurial pursuits by assessing unmet clinical needs. There is tremendous opportunity in many fields of healthcare for new devices, diagnostics, and therapeutics.</p>
<p>A new device that significantly improves efficiency and reduces costs, such as allowing treatment to move from in-patient to an out-patient procedure, will be welcomed by patients, clinicians, and payers alike. However, a new device that provides only incremental improvements will likely be challenging to get past value assessment committees or adopted by clinicians.</p>
<p><span class="Apple-converted-space"> </span></p>
<p>A new diagnostic test will be embraced if it enters a clinical domain and market that was unserved or poorly served, and it improves the quality of medical decision-making and treatment.<span class="Apple-converted-space">  </span>However, a new diagnostic test may be limited in acceptance if there is no effective treatment to implement when a diagnosis is made with the new test or if the cost of the test is too high.</p>
<p>A new drug that improves treatment and patient outcomes in an underserved clinical domain and market is likely to be adopted quickly.<span class="Apple-converted-space">  </span>However, a new drug may be adopted slowly, even in a poorly served market, if it is crowded with established standard treatments.<span class="Apple-converted-space">  </span>Treatment guidelines, conservative physicians, and payors may require that patients exhaust existing treatment options before trying the new drug.</p>
<p>Assessing the size of the market, competition, and costs associated with bringing a product to market to address an unmet clinical need will allow you to determine if it is a “business-viable” unmet clinical need.<span class="Apple-converted-space">  </span>Watch for upcoming articles in this series to help you with the next steps.</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://davekuhar.github.io/bbic/2019/11/14/unmet-clinical-need/">Specialist Series: Unmet Clinical Need</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://davekuhar.github.io/bbic/">Boston Biomedical Innovation Center</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>B-BIC: &#8216;IS MORE THAN JUST FUNDING&#8217;, with Kantum Pharma</title>
		<link>https://davekuhar.github.io/bbic/2019/10/14/b-bic-is-more-than-just-funding-with-kantum-pharma/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[B-BIC]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Mon, 14 Oct 2019 17:13:27 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[News]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Success Stories]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Kantum]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Kantum Pharma]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Video]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[web video]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://b-bic.org/?p=1278</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>We are thrilled to share with you a new web video we are releasing that highlights our &#8216;Commercialization Coaches&#8217; and other services that are ways B-BIC successfully differentiates from other grants. Kantum Pharma, dedicated to the prevention and treatment of Acute Kidney Injury, received its first B-BIC Pilot grant in 2017.</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://davekuhar.github.io/bbic/2019/10/14/b-bic-is-more-than-just-funding-with-kantum-pharma/">B-BIC: &#8216;IS MORE THAN JUST FUNDING&#8217;, with Kantum Pharma</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://davekuhar.github.io/bbic/">Boston Biomedical Innovation Center</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<div>We are thrilled to share with you a new web video we are releasing that highlights our &#8216;Commercialization Coaches&#8217; and other services that are ways B-BIC successfully differentiates from other grants.</div>
<div></div>
<div><a href="https://www.kantumpharma.com/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer" data-link-type="web">Kantum Pharma</a>, dedicated to the prevention and treatment of Acute Kidney Injury, received its first B-BIC Pilot grant in 2017.</div>
<div></div>
<div>
<p><iframe loading="lazy" title="B-BIC:  MORE THAN JUST FUNDING with Kantum Pharma" width="500" height="281" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/aSD_O_BEl8I?feature=oembed" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture" allowfullscreen></iframe></p>
</div>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://davekuhar.github.io/bbic/2019/10/14/b-bic-is-more-than-just-funding-with-kantum-pharma/">B-BIC: &#8216;IS MORE THAN JUST FUNDING&#8217;, with Kantum Pharma</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://davekuhar.github.io/bbic/">Boston Biomedical Innovation Center</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Specialist Series: Technology in Search of an Application</title>
		<link>https://davekuhar.github.io/bbic/2019/10/09/specialist-series-technology-in-search-of-an-application/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[B-BIC]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 09 Oct 2019 14:04:51 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Specialist Series]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[specialist series]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://b-bic.org/?p=1276</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Technology in Search of an Application Part II of the Specialist Series: The Road to Commercialization: Challenges and Opportunities Written by John Randle Development models always start with addressing clinical needs, but scientific discoveries and technological advances typically happen independently from solving clinical problems. This article will explore ways you can ensure that you are&#8230;</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://davekuhar.github.io/bbic/2019/10/09/specialist-series-technology-in-search-of-an-application/">Specialist Series: Technology in Search of an Application</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://davekuhar.github.io/bbic/">Boston Biomedical Innovation Center</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><strong><span data-preserver-spaces="true">Technology in Search of an Application</span></strong></p>
<p>Part II of the Specialist Series: The Road to Commercialization: Challenges and Opportunities</p>
<p>Written by John Randle</p>
<p><em><span data-preserver-spaces="true">Development models always start with addressing clinical needs, but scientific discoveries and technological advances typically happen independently from solving clinical problems. This article will explore ways you can ensure that you are connecting the promising technology you are developing, to addressing viable clinical needs.  </span></em></p>
<p><span data-preserver-spaces="true">Some visionary tech developers would have you believe that they envisioned a brave new world where their product created or filled a need that people didn’t know they had. In the reality of medical product development, this is rarely the case. The medical literature is replete with introductory paragraphs that explicitly identify medical needs, as well as others that describe how current products only partially address medical needs. The latter may be deficient in efficacy, adverse effect profile, convenience, cost and/or other characteristics. </span></p>
<p><span data-preserver-spaces="true">Opposite these medical needs is the long list of existing and emerging technologies. The key strategic insight in medical product development is the decision to orient the use of one or more technologies to the medical need(s) where they can have the highest medical impact, and as a consequence, be most likely to be commercially successful.</span></p>
<p><span data-preserver-spaces="true">In device development, new sensor and measurement technologies are frequently developed by researchers. Since the technologies are typically based on low-cost silicon processes, and are small and low power, the researches often believe the technology can revolutionize care by providing direct-to-consumer devices that can provide information to the consumer’s physicians. In reality, physicians have been skeptical of data from consumer devices and are unable to handle the volume of data provided. Applying new sensor and measurement technologies to delivering more cost-effective, rapid, and convenient measurements in the clinical setting has been much more successful.</span></p>
<p><span data-preserver-spaces="true">In diagnostic development, new biomarkers may be identified by researchers working in a specific disease area. They may attempt to demonstrate an association or causal relationship between the biomarker and particular conditions. However, apart from genetic markers of select diseases, such biomarkers may well find utility in related disease entities or entirely different specialties, sometimes more significant than in the initial indication. This may occur if the drivers of the biomarker turn out to be different from those initially expected by the researchers working in a given disease area. An example is a C-reactive protein, first identified and widely used as a marker of inflammation useful in rheumatology, but later crossing over as a diagnostic for risk of cardiac events. </span></p>
<p><span data-preserver-spaces="true">In pharmaceutical discovery and development, when a new molecular drug target is identified, researchers often hypothesize that a drug interacting with that target will have a beneficial effect in a particular therapeutic indication. However, identifying the diseases in which a targeted therapy will be useful is often impaired at this early time by incomplete knowledge of the physiology of the target. A well-known example is the phosphodiesterase-5 inhibitors that were initially studied as anti-angina drugs but were fortuitously discovered to have the potential to treat erectile dysfunction. There are many examples of targets expected to be useful in inflammatory and autoimmune diseases, as well as in oncology, which has undergone clinical testing in many indications before finding a home in one or more of these. The trick in these disease areas has been to determine in which diseases, and even in which patients, the target is a key driver of the disease and, thus, a useful drug target.  </span></p>
<p><span data-preserver-spaces="true">The unifying theme of all these examples is that researchers and product developers focused on technologies should keep open minds about how their technology can best be married to a medical need for which it can be most impactful. Conversely, researchers focused on specific medical needs to do well to scan emerging technologies to identify technologies potentially useful in their area. This is only initially an intellectual exercise. Instead, it usually plays out in the product development process, starting at the pilot/preclinical phase and ultimately requiring clinical testing to confirm the best fit between technology and medical applications.</span></p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://davekuhar.github.io/bbic/2019/10/09/specialist-series-technology-in-search-of-an-application/">Specialist Series: Technology in Search of an Application</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://davekuhar.github.io/bbic/">Boston Biomedical Innovation Center</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>NEW AWARD:  Congratulations Dr. Nelson Ruiz-Opazo!!</title>
		<link>https://davekuhar.github.io/bbic/2019/09/02/new-award-congratulations-dr-nelson-ruiz-opazo-2/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[B-BIC]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Mon, 02 Sep 2019 14:42:53 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[News]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://b-bic.org/?p=1249</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>TITLE: Humanized anti-DEspR antibody therapy for acute respiratory distress syndrome TYPE OF AWARD: Drive CLINICAL AREA:  Lung INSTITUTION: Boston University DESCRIPTION: Acute respiratory distress syndrome (ARDS) and its progression to multi-organ failure (MOF) affects ~200,000 ICU patients each year in the US, with high mortality and healthcare costs. ARDS is driven by hyperinflammation-injury cycles that begin as a normal injury&#8230;</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://davekuhar.github.io/bbic/2019/09/02/new-award-congratulations-dr-nelson-ruiz-opazo-2/">NEW AWARD:  Congratulations Dr. Nelson Ruiz-Opazo!!</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://davekuhar.github.io/bbic/">Boston Biomedical Innovation Center</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<div>
<div><strong>TITLE</strong>: Humanized anti-DEspR antibody therapy for acute respiratory distress syndrome</div>
<div><strong>TYPE OF AWARD: </strong>Drive</div>
<div><strong>CLINICAL AREA:</strong>  Lung</div>
<div><strong>INSTITUTION:</strong> Boston University</div>
</div>
<p><strong>DESCRIPTION</strong>: Acute respiratory distress syndrome (ARDS) and its progression to multi-organ failure (MOF) affects ~200,000 ICU patients each year in the US, with high mortality and healthcare costs. ARDS is driven by hyperinflammation-injury cycles that begin as a normal injury response but become dysregulated causing secondary-tissue injury in the lung and other vital organs, culminating in MOF and death. An actionable key culprit that drives secondary-tissue injury is the activated neutrophil that continually releases bacterio/cyto-toxic enzymes. To date, there is no pharmacotherapy to stop neutrophil-driven secondary-tissue injury in ARDS-MOF. DEspR (Dual Endothelin-1/signal peptide Receptor) is a receptor for endothelin-1 and VEGF-signal peptide expressed by activated neutrophils as a survival factor that allows them to escape apoptosis and perpetuate vicious cycles of secondary-tissue injury in ARDS. Our B-BIC Pilot project provided proof-of-concept data that ABTM-468, a humanized-IgG4[S228P] anti-DEspR antibody, reduces the survival of an activated-neutrophil subset associated with poor outcomes, and reduced downstream components of a vicious cycle. Thus, ABTM468 may stop hyper-inflammatory vicious cycles in ARDS. In this DRIVE proposal, we aim to advance the testing of ABTM-468 efficacy ex vivo in ARDS patient blood samples to confirm and extend the Pilot efficacy data (Aim 1), identify biomarkers of responders and surrogate markers of early response and toxicity (Aim 2), and test for involvement in lung injury from the epithelial side (Aim 3). These data will provide a solid foundation for the clinical development of ABTM-468 in ARDS.</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://davekuhar.github.io/bbic/2019/09/02/new-award-congratulations-dr-nelson-ruiz-opazo-2/">NEW AWARD:  Congratulations Dr. Nelson Ruiz-Opazo!!</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://davekuhar.github.io/bbic/">Boston Biomedical Innovation Center</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>NEW AWARD: Congratulations Dr. Steven Greenberg!!</title>
		<link>https://davekuhar.github.io/bbic/2019/09/02/new-award-congratulations-dr-steven-greenberg/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[B-BIC]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Mon, 02 Sep 2019 14:41:29 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[New Award]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://b-bic.org/?p=1247</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>TITLE: Generation of a Novel Therapeutic Antibody for Treatment of Allergic Asthma TYPE OF AWARD: Pilot CLINICAL AREA:  Lung INSTITUTION: Brigham and Women&#8217;s Hospital &#160; DESCRIPTION: Asthma affects 8% of the US population, approximately 25 million people. About 10% of patients have severe asthma, accounting for an estimated 1.8 million emergency department visits, 439,000 hospitalizations, and 3,630 deaths annually&#8230;</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://davekuhar.github.io/bbic/2019/09/02/new-award-congratulations-dr-steven-greenberg/">NEW AWARD: Congratulations Dr. Steven Greenberg!!</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://davekuhar.github.io/bbic/">Boston Biomedical Innovation Center</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<div>
<div><strong>TITLE</strong>: Generation of a Novel Therapeutic Antibody for Treatment of Allergic Asthma</div>
<div><strong>TYPE OF AWARD:</strong> Pilot</div>
<div><strong>CLINICAL AREA:</strong>  Lung</div>
<div><strong>INSTITUTION:</strong> Brigham and Women&#8217;s Hospital</div>
</div>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p><strong>DESCRIPTION</strong>:</p>
<p class="x_MsoNormal">Asthma affects 8% of the US population, approximately 25 million people. About 10% of patients have severe asthma, accounting for an estimated 1.8 million emergency department visits, 439,000 hospitalizations, and 3,630 deaths annually in the US [1].</p>
<p class="x_MsoNormal">Airway inflammation in asthma can be classified as either eosinophilic or non-eosinophilic. Eosinophilic asthma is driven by Th2 mechanisms sustained by innate lymphoid cells type 2 (ILC2) and pathogenic effector Th2 (pETh2) cells’ production of interleukin 5 (IL-5), leading to bronchial eosinophilia. Non-eosinophilic asthma is less well understood but Th17 pathways are a major contributor, responsible for neutrophilic infiltration of the airways [2].</p>
<p class="x_MsoNormal">
<p class="x_MsoNormal">The proposed technology is designed to treat both eosinophilic and non-eosinophilic asthma via a therapeutic monoclonal antibody (mAb) designed to work via targeting depletion of innate lymphoid cells type 2 (ILC2), pathogenic effector Th2 (pETh2) cells, and Th17 cells.</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://davekuhar.github.io/bbic/2019/09/02/new-award-congratulations-dr-steven-greenberg/">NEW AWARD: Congratulations Dr. Steven Greenberg!!</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://davekuhar.github.io/bbic/">Boston Biomedical Innovation Center</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
