<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	>

<channel>
	<title>News &#8211; Boston Biomedical Innovation Center</title>
	<atom:link href="https://davekuhar.github.io/bbic/category/news/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>https://davekuhar.github.io/bbic/</link>
	<description></description>
	<lastBuildDate>Mon, 23 Mar 2020 15:53:31 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>
	hourly	</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>
	1	</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>https://wordpress.org/?v=5.8.1</generator>

<image>
	<url>https://davekuhar.github.io/bbic/wp-content/uploads/2016/11/cropped-bbic-favicon-32x32.png</url>
	<title>News &#8211; Boston Biomedical Innovation Center</title>
	<link>https://davekuhar.github.io/bbic/</link>
	<width>32</width>
	<height>32</height>
</image> 
	<item>
		<title>New Award: Congratulations Bradley Maron, MD!</title>
		<link>https://davekuhar.github.io/bbic/2020/01/13/new-award-congratulations-bradley-maron-md/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[B-BIC]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Mon, 13 Jan 2020 17:47:48 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[New Award]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[News]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://b-bic.org/?p=1291</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>TITLE: NEDD9 Monoclonal Antibody Therapeutic for Pulmonary Thromboembolic Disease TYPE OF AWARD: Drive CLINICAL AREA:  Biologic INSTITUTION: Brigham and Women&#8217;s Hospital DESCRIPTION: Increased platelet-endothelial adhesion is a central pathobiological event underlying the pathogenesis of pulmonary arterial hypertension (PAH) and chronic thromboembolic pulmonary hypertension (CTEPH). Current therapies to treat thrombosis in PAH and CTEPH emphasize non-specific coagulation proteins, and are associated&#8230;</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://davekuhar.github.io/bbic/2020/01/13/new-award-congratulations-bradley-maron-md/">New Award: Congratulations Bradley Maron, MD!</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://davekuhar.github.io/bbic/">Boston Biomedical Innovation Center</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<div><strong>TITLE: </strong>NEDD9 Monoclonal Antibody Therapeutic for Pulmonary Thromboembolic Disease</div>
<div><strong>TYPE OF AWARD:</strong> Drive</div>
<div><strong>CLINICAL AREA: </strong> Biologic</div>
<div><strong>INSTITUTION</strong>: Brigham and Women&#8217;s Hospital</div>
<div></div>
<div></div>
<div><strong>DESCRIPTION</strong>: Increased platelet-endothelial adhesion is a central pathobiological event underlying the pathogenesis of pulmonary arterial hypertension (PAH) and chronic thromboembolic pulmonary hypertension (CTEPH). Current therapies to treat thrombosis in PAH and CTEPH emphasize non-specific coagulation proteins, and are associated with elevated rates of off-target effects (e.g., intracranial hemorrhage). Developing a pulmonary vascular-specific drug has several high impact and favorable advantages to current standard of care, but such therapies not exist currently. In this proposal, we present novel data demonstrating that the substrate domain of the protein NEDD9 is a modifiable target to limit thrombosis selectively in the pulmonary circulation. Specifically, our data suggests that NEDD9 on the outward facing plasma membrane is increased by hypoxia selectively in human pulmonary artery endothelial cells, which, in turn, functions as a target of platelet P-selectin to modulate platelet-endothelial interactions in vitro and pulmonary thrombosis in vivo.</div>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p>We propose experiments using PAH and CTEPH animal models and patient samples to profile the therapeutic effect of a novel monoclonal antibody against the pro-thrombotic NEDD9 peptide sequence (mAb-NEDD9). Go/No-go decisions, pivot points and milestone markers are detailed in the accompanying proposal. Overall, results of the proposed experiments aim to i) establish NEDD9 as a druggable site to inhibit thrombosis in PAH and CTEPH, ii) develop a high quality mAb-NEDD9, and iii) demonstrate that the mAb-NEDD9 inhibits platelet adhesion to pulmonary artery endothelial cells in vitro and inhibits thrombosis, vascular remodeling, and pulmonary hypertension in PAH/CTEPH animal models in vivo. Deliverables from this project will be well positioned for early clinical testing.</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://davekuhar.github.io/bbic/2020/01/13/new-award-congratulations-bradley-maron-md/">New Award: Congratulations Bradley Maron, MD!</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://davekuhar.github.io/bbic/">Boston Biomedical Innovation Center</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>B-BIC: &#8216;IS MORE THAN JUST FUNDING&#8217;, with Kantum Pharma</title>
		<link>https://davekuhar.github.io/bbic/2019/10/14/b-bic-is-more-than-just-funding-with-kantum-pharma/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[B-BIC]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Mon, 14 Oct 2019 17:13:27 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[News]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Success Stories]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Kantum]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Kantum Pharma]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Video]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[web video]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://b-bic.org/?p=1278</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>We are thrilled to share with you a new web video we are releasing that highlights our &#8216;Commercialization Coaches&#8217; and other services that are ways B-BIC successfully differentiates from other grants. Kantum Pharma, dedicated to the prevention and treatment of Acute Kidney Injury, received its first B-BIC Pilot grant in 2017.</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://davekuhar.github.io/bbic/2019/10/14/b-bic-is-more-than-just-funding-with-kantum-pharma/">B-BIC: &#8216;IS MORE THAN JUST FUNDING&#8217;, with Kantum Pharma</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://davekuhar.github.io/bbic/">Boston Biomedical Innovation Center</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<div>We are thrilled to share with you a new web video we are releasing that highlights our &#8216;Commercialization Coaches&#8217; and other services that are ways B-BIC successfully differentiates from other grants.</div>
<div></div>
<div><a href="https://www.kantumpharma.com/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer" data-link-type="web">Kantum Pharma</a>, dedicated to the prevention and treatment of Acute Kidney Injury, received its first B-BIC Pilot grant in 2017.</div>
<div></div>
<div>
<p><iframe loading="lazy" title="B-BIC:  MORE THAN JUST FUNDING with Kantum Pharma" width="500" height="281" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/aSD_O_BEl8I?feature=oembed" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture" allowfullscreen></iframe></p>
</div>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://davekuhar.github.io/bbic/2019/10/14/b-bic-is-more-than-just-funding-with-kantum-pharma/">B-BIC: &#8216;IS MORE THAN JUST FUNDING&#8217;, with Kantum Pharma</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://davekuhar.github.io/bbic/">Boston Biomedical Innovation Center</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>NEW AWARD:  Congratulations Dr. Nelson Ruiz-Opazo!!</title>
		<link>https://davekuhar.github.io/bbic/2019/09/02/new-award-congratulations-dr-nelson-ruiz-opazo-2/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[B-BIC]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Mon, 02 Sep 2019 14:42:53 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[News]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://b-bic.org/?p=1249</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>TITLE: Humanized anti-DEspR antibody therapy for acute respiratory distress syndrome TYPE OF AWARD: Drive CLINICAL AREA:  Lung INSTITUTION: Boston University DESCRIPTION: Acute respiratory distress syndrome (ARDS) and its progression to multi-organ failure (MOF) affects ~200,000 ICU patients each year in the US, with high mortality and healthcare costs. ARDS is driven by hyperinflammation-injury cycles that begin as a normal injury&#8230;</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://davekuhar.github.io/bbic/2019/09/02/new-award-congratulations-dr-nelson-ruiz-opazo-2/">NEW AWARD:  Congratulations Dr. Nelson Ruiz-Opazo!!</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://davekuhar.github.io/bbic/">Boston Biomedical Innovation Center</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<div>
<div><strong>TITLE</strong>: Humanized anti-DEspR antibody therapy for acute respiratory distress syndrome</div>
<div><strong>TYPE OF AWARD: </strong>Drive</div>
<div><strong>CLINICAL AREA:</strong>  Lung</div>
<div><strong>INSTITUTION:</strong> Boston University</div>
</div>
<p><strong>DESCRIPTION</strong>: Acute respiratory distress syndrome (ARDS) and its progression to multi-organ failure (MOF) affects ~200,000 ICU patients each year in the US, with high mortality and healthcare costs. ARDS is driven by hyperinflammation-injury cycles that begin as a normal injury response but become dysregulated causing secondary-tissue injury in the lung and other vital organs, culminating in MOF and death. An actionable key culprit that drives secondary-tissue injury is the activated neutrophil that continually releases bacterio/cyto-toxic enzymes. To date, there is no pharmacotherapy to stop neutrophil-driven secondary-tissue injury in ARDS-MOF. DEspR (Dual Endothelin-1/signal peptide Receptor) is a receptor for endothelin-1 and VEGF-signal peptide expressed by activated neutrophils as a survival factor that allows them to escape apoptosis and perpetuate vicious cycles of secondary-tissue injury in ARDS. Our B-BIC Pilot project provided proof-of-concept data that ABTM-468, a humanized-IgG4[S228P] anti-DEspR antibody, reduces the survival of an activated-neutrophil subset associated with poor outcomes, and reduced downstream components of a vicious cycle. Thus, ABTM468 may stop hyper-inflammatory vicious cycles in ARDS. In this DRIVE proposal, we aim to advance the testing of ABTM-468 efficacy ex vivo in ARDS patient blood samples to confirm and extend the Pilot efficacy data (Aim 1), identify biomarkers of responders and surrogate markers of early response and toxicity (Aim 2), and test for involvement in lung injury from the epithelial side (Aim 3). These data will provide a solid foundation for the clinical development of ABTM-468 in ARDS.</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://davekuhar.github.io/bbic/2019/09/02/new-award-congratulations-dr-nelson-ruiz-opazo-2/">NEW AWARD:  Congratulations Dr. Nelson Ruiz-Opazo!!</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://davekuhar.github.io/bbic/">Boston Biomedical Innovation Center</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Specialist Series: The Breakdown of a B-BIC Proposal / Business Plan</title>
		<link>https://davekuhar.github.io/bbic/2019/09/02/1241/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[B-BIC]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Mon, 02 Sep 2019 14:17:57 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[News]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Specialist Series]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Application]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[business plan]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://b-bic.org/?p=1241</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Over the course of 2019, our coaches and staff broke down the B-BIC application process to provide you with expert advice on all the of the questions we ask you to answer when applying for our program. For those who are not applying yet, the B-BIC proposal has many similarities to a business plan, which&#8230;</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://davekuhar.github.io/bbic/2019/09/02/1241/">Specialist Series: The Breakdown of a B-BIC Proposal / Business Plan</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://davekuhar.github.io/bbic/">Boston Biomedical Innovation Center</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Over the course of 2019, our coaches and staff broke down the B-BIC application process to provide you with expert advice on all the of the questions we ask you to answer when applying for our program. For those who are not applying yet, the B-BIC proposal has many similarities to a business plan, which we hope will be very helpful to your efforts as you proceed.</p>
<p>All Articles Within Our Series</p>
<ul>
<li><a href="https://b-bic.org/2017/10/30/build-effective-overview-technology/">How To Build An Effective Overview For Your Technology</a></li>
<li><a href="https://b-bic.org/2017/11/10/specialist-series-finding-defining-unmet-need/">Finding And Defining Your Unmet Need</a></li>
<li><a href="https://b-bic.org/2017/12/11/filling-unmet-need-proposed-solution/">Explaining Your Proposed Solution To That Unmet Need</a></li>
<li><a href="https://b-bic.org/2018/01/31/specialist-series-defining-competitive-landscape/">Defining Your Competitive Landscape</a></li>
<li><a href="https://b-bic.org/2018/03/01/specialist-series-defining-market/">Defining Your Market</a></li>
<li><a href="https://b-bic.org/2018/04/17/specialist-series-the-regulatory-path/">Regulatory Path</a></li>
<li><a href="https://b-bic.org/2018/09/11/specialist-series-a-brief-introduction-to-intellectual-property/">Intellectual Property</a></li>
<li><a href="https://b-bic.org/2018/10/19/reimbursement-basics/">Reimbursement Basics</a></li>
<li><a href="https://b-bic.org/2018/11/13/specialist-series-project-management/">Building your Project Plan</a></li>
<li><a href="https://b-bic.org/2019/01/07/understanding-and-articulating-your-financials-and-funding-requirement/">Understanding/ Articulating Your Financials And Funding Requirements</a></li>
<li><a href="https://b-bic.org/2019/02/21/venture-adventure-exploring-the-role-of-the-inventor-in-commercialization/">Defining Your Role</a></li>
</ul>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://davekuhar.github.io/bbic/2019/09/02/1241/">Specialist Series: The Breakdown of a B-BIC Proposal / Business Plan</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://davekuhar.github.io/bbic/">Boston Biomedical Innovation Center</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>New Award: Congratulations Benjamin Matthews, M.D.!</title>
		<link>https://davekuhar.github.io/bbic/2019/02/21/new-award-congratulations-benjamin-matthews-m-d/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[B-BIC]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 21 Feb 2019 14:08:49 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[News]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://b-bic.org/?p=1201</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>TITLE: PR1P, an inhaled novel short peptide for Acute Lung Injury and ARDS. TYPE OF AWARD: Drive TECHNOLOGY TYPE: Small Molecule CLINICAL AREA:  Lung INSTITUTION: Boston Children&#8217;s Hospital DESCRIPTION:ARDS is an acute inflammatory lung disease characterized by hypoxemia and multi-organ failure with mortality reaching 50%. It accounts for almost 200,000 ICU admissions yearly in the US and&#8230;</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://davekuhar.github.io/bbic/2019/02/21/new-award-congratulations-benjamin-matthews-m-d/">New Award: Congratulations Benjamin Matthews, M.D.!</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://davekuhar.github.io/bbic/">Boston Biomedical Innovation Center</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<header class="fl-post-header">
<div><strong>TITLE:</strong> PR1P, an inhaled novel short peptide for Acute Lung Injury and ARDS.</div>
<div><strong>TYPE OF AWARD:</strong> Drive</div>
<div><strong>TECHNOLOGY TYPE:</strong> Small Molecule</div>
<div><strong>CLINICAL AREA:</strong>  Lung</div>
<div><strong>INSTITUTION:</strong> Boston Children&#8217;s Hospital</div>
</header>
<div class="fl-post-content clearfix">
<div></div>
<div>
<div><strong>DESCRIPTION:</strong>ARDS is an acute inflammatory lung disease characterized by hypoxemia and multi-organ failure with mortality reaching 50%. It accounts for almost 200,000 ICU admissions yearly in the US and thus impacts substantially on healthcare cost. Importantly, there are no drugs that treat ARDS. Disease progression is due in part to the dysregulation of the Vascular Endothelial Growth Factor (VEGF). We recently designed a novel short peptide, PR1P, that binds and upregulates endogenous VEGF signaling. Preliminary work from our BBIC Pilot grant showed that inhaled PR1P mitigated acute lung injury (ALI) in an elastase-induced murine emphysema model. We hypothesize that PR1P will be therapeutic in humans with ARDS. The peptide requires proof-of-principle testing in animal and human models. We propose herein Aim 1 to characterize the effect of inhaled PR1P on disease progression in three established murine ARDS models, and in Aim 2 to determine if the therapeutic activity of the peptide is preserved in tissue samples from patients with ARDS. Mice will be treated with inhaled PR1P at different stages of the disease to mimic treatment start times of patients presenting with ARDS. We will characterize the ability of PR1P to mitigate disease severity including 1) lung cell apoptosis and lung 2) inflammation, 3) permeability and 4) damage. Our overall goal is to determine that PR1P mitigates murine ALI and is functional in human tissue samples. If successful, this will provide the proofs of concept necessary to support investment in PR1P for use in humans with ARDS.</div>
</div>
</div>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://davekuhar.github.io/bbic/2019/02/21/new-award-congratulations-benjamin-matthews-m-d/">New Award: Congratulations Benjamin Matthews, M.D.!</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://davekuhar.github.io/bbic/">Boston Biomedical Innovation Center</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Specialist Series: Venture Adventure &#8211; Exploring the Role of the Inventor in Commercialization</title>
		<link>https://davekuhar.github.io/bbic/2019/02/21/venture-adventure-exploring-the-role-of-the-inventor-in-commercialization/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[B-BIC]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 21 Feb 2019 13:58:16 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[News]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Specialist Series]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Role]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[specialist series]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[venture]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://b-bic.org/?p=1197</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Written by Carl Berke, PhD. Partner at the Partners Innovation Fund Thomas Edison famously remarked, “Invention is 1% inspiration and 99% perspiration”. The Wizard of Menlo Park was a prolific inventor who never left his lab, but his intellectual property was adopted by a plethora of companies who translated his technology into products that delighted&#8230;</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://davekuhar.github.io/bbic/2019/02/21/venture-adventure-exploring-the-role-of-the-inventor-in-commercialization/">Specialist Series: Venture Adventure &#8211; Exploring the Role of the Inventor in Commercialization</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://davekuhar.github.io/bbic/">Boston Biomedical Innovation Center</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Written by Carl Berke, PhD.</p>
<p>Partner at the <a href="http://www.partnersinnovationfund.com/">Partners Innovation Fund</a></p>
<p>Thomas Edison famously remarked, “Invention is 1% inspiration and 99% perspiration”. The Wizard of Menlo Park was a prolific inventor who never left his lab, but his intellectual property was adopted by a plethora of companies who translated his technology into products that delighted the public. Stats from the Partners investigator community indicate more than 1000 disclosures are filed a year which yield more than 250 patents a year. About 35% of those patents eventually go under license to companies intending to develop a product protected by exclusive right to bring it to market. In most cases, the first licensee is a company at the early formation stage who wish, and often require, the participation of the inventor in the transition process and beyond. There is a continuous spectrum of options for inventor involvement that varies based on the mutual needs and desires of the founding team. The IP is the sole property of the inventor’s institution, the licensor, but any proceeds from the license are distributed, according to policy, amongst the inventors, the hospital and the inventors’ department.</p>
<p>Typically, an inventor who is part of a founder team will be offered a grant of common shares that reflects their contribution, beyond the IP creation, to the company through the arduous process of planning, fundraising, and formation. The quantity of shares [i.e., percent of company ownership] allocated is a matter of negotiation amongst the individuals of the founding team. Once the company begins operations, the inventor is often engaged as a consultant and member of the Scientific Advisory Board. The consulting contract is typically overseen by the institution to ensure compliance with conflict of interest policy. There may be additional founder equity granted to the inventor-founder as compensation for these consulting services in lieu of cash.</p>
<p>The new company will seek to recruit individuals into management with extensive industry experience who understand the protocols of drug, device, diagnostic or digital product development necessary to advance a program through the stringent FDA regulatory process. This kind of knowledge is highly specialized and generally not familiar to scientists in the academic setting and should be appreciated as comparable in importance to the success of the enterprise.</p>
<p>Academic institutional policy generally prohibits full-time employees from taking management positions in the company and limits consulting time to no more than one day/week. However, board of director service is permitted. In a few cases, faculty has crossed over to company employment usually because the stage of technology development is still so early as to require the research skills and knowledge of the inventor to ensure the success of the program. This is more common for post-doctoral fellows than PIs, but a recent case in point is Andrew Bellinger, MD, Ph.D., a cardiologist who helped to conceive a new technology platform for oral drug delivery with collaborators at MIT. Andrew recently joined Lyndra Therapeutics as Chief Scientific Officer and has led the effort to bring their first prototype to the clinic. He retains his BWH appointment so he can still spend a day a week with patients.</p>
<p>From a different context, Dr. Jonathan Thon, Ph.D., saw the potential for applying his postdoctoral research to the problem of chronic shortages in the human blood platelet supply. While working in the laboratory of Dr. Joe Italiano at BWH, he conceived a plan to develop an in vitro culture process that could be scaled up to the commercial stage. Jonathan entered the B-BIC program along with a business partner where they received additional training, coaching, and resources to create a feasibility data package and focused business plan that would attract venture investment. Jonathan transitioned out of BWH into the company, Platelet Biogenesis Inc, as Chief Executive Officer and his former PI, Dr. Italiano, serves on the Board of Directors.</p>
<p>Occasionally, a licensee company determines that the best way forward is via clinical trial directed by the original clinician-inventor. Our institutional conflict-of-interest rules prohibit investigators from conducting clinical research that is sponsored by companies in which they have any ownership. Under Harvard Medical School rules, exceptions can be granted according to the “rebuttable proposition” rule if it can be shown that there is no reasonable alternative – in those cases, special management measures are put in place to guard patient best interest. Similarly, investigators are not permitted to accept sponsored research from companies in which they hold equity as this can be considered private gain from publicly funded resources.</p>
<p>The product development pathway is a journey. It originates in the PI laboratory and at some point may cross the river of incorporation to continue on a different landscape towards the goal of market entry and actual impact on healthcare. The opportunities for inventors to participate along the way are highly situational but should be regarded as another means to fulfill both personal and professional goals. It is the mission of B-BIC to collaborate with investigators to support the creation of opportunities to transform intellectual property emerging from our research community into future products that benefit patients.</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://davekuhar.github.io/bbic/2019/02/21/venture-adventure-exploring-the-role-of-the-inventor-in-commercialization/">Specialist Series: Venture Adventure &#8211; Exploring the Role of the Inventor in Commercialization</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://davekuhar.github.io/bbic/">Boston Biomedical Innovation Center</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Specialist Series: Understanding And Articulating Your Financials And Funding Requirements</title>
		<link>https://davekuhar.github.io/bbic/2019/01/07/understanding-and-articulating-your-financials-and-funding-requirement/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[B-BIC]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Mon, 07 Jan 2019 15:43:24 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[News]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Specialist Series]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Business Plan Series]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Specialist Article]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[specialist series]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://b-bic.org/?p=1181</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>By Lesley Watts When describing the financial support necessary to develop a technology, the first step is to be clear about the scope of the work you are addressing, as no single source of funding will be able to support all of the associated R&#38;D costs.  Anyone who is assessing your project plan will want&#8230;</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://davekuhar.github.io/bbic/2019/01/07/understanding-and-articulating-your-financials-and-funding-requirement/">Specialist Series: Understanding And Articulating Your Financials And Funding Requirements</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://davekuhar.github.io/bbic/">Boston Biomedical Innovation Center</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><i>By Lesley Watts</i></p>
<p>When describing the financial support necessary to develop a technology, the first step is to be clear about the scope of the work you are addressing, as no single source of funding will be able to support all of the associated R&amp;D costs.  Anyone who is assessing your project plan will want to see that you are aware of this and that you have a rough idea as to how you will continue to move forward once you have fully expended the source of support. To do this, you should begin by letting your reviewers know the aspect of the technology’s development that will be supported with the funds you are requesting.</p>
<p>Once the project plan and methods are sketched out and the associated costs can be reasonably estimated, describe the specific objectives that will be supported by these costs. Reviewers want to see the work associated with milestones and appropriate decision points. They will want to look at funds that could be re-directed should a change in the project’s course become necessary as a consequence of results obtained earlier in the project plan. For example, if a specific milestone is expected to take one-third of the project period to complete, it may be appropriate to associate one-third of the relevant personnel costs with that milestone. Similarly, if a milestone includes work that is to be conducted by an outside entity, associate the payment of that vendor with that milestone.</p>
<p>Be realistic when describing the financial requirements of the current project plan. Reviewers will want to see that the funds requested are sufficient to support the work described in the application. If you propose a scope of work that requires resources that greatly exceed your request, a reviewer may believe you are naïve, unaware of what is needed, and that you will not be able to complete the work you have described.</p>
<p>If you are planning to leverage additional resources to complete the described project plan, be sure to provide evidence of their availability. Evidence can be in the form of a letter of support from the facilities that will be contributing the additional resources, or it can be a clear-cut statement in the budget justification.  However, be sure to check with your institution or company before offering additional resources to supplement what you are requesting to support the proposed project plan. The commitment of additional resources beyond what is required by the sponsor may incur significant reporting requirements, and it may be discouraged.</p>
<p>Finally, describe how the project plan and the support requested will fit into the overall picture and development plan for the technology. The reviewers will want to know that you are aware of the follow-on work that will be needed; they will want to know that the work will not simply end when the award ends. At a high level, describe the next steps for technology development and provide a rough estimate of the costs associated with achieving the next inflection points described in the overall development plan, and be as realistic as possible.</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://davekuhar.github.io/bbic/2019/01/07/understanding-and-articulating-your-financials-and-funding-requirement/">Specialist Series: Understanding And Articulating Your Financials And Funding Requirements</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://davekuhar.github.io/bbic/">Boston Biomedical Innovation Center</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Success Stories:  B-BIC&#8217;s Work With Platelet Biogenesis</title>
		<link>https://davekuhar.github.io/bbic/2018/09/11/success-stories-b-bics-work-with-platelet-biogenesis/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[B-BIC]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 11 Sep 2018 23:35:20 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[News]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Success Stories]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Platelet Biogenesis]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://b-bic.org/?p=1154</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>WATCH:  B-BIC&#8217;s Work With Platelet Biogenesis One of B-BIC’s first grant recipients was Jonathan Thon, a researcher based at Brigham and Women’s Hospital. Jonathan and his team had been researching two technologies necessary for producing platelets outside of the body. They had achieved promising results that demonstrated a microfluidic platform could simulate bone marrow physiological&#8230;</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://davekuhar.github.io/bbic/2018/09/11/success-stories-b-bics-work-with-platelet-biogenesis/">Success Stories:  B-BIC&#8217;s Work With Platelet Biogenesis</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://davekuhar.github.io/bbic/">Boston Biomedical Innovation Center</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<div><a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=0weu4E4lZCY">WATCH:  B-BIC&#8217;s Work With Platelet Biogenesis</a></div>
<div></div>
<div></div>
<div>One of B-BIC’s first grant recipients was Jonathan Thon, a researcher based at Brigham and Women’s Hospital. Jonathan and his team had been researching two technologies necessary for producing platelets outside of the body. They had achieved promising results that demonstrated a microfluidic platform could simulate bone marrow physiological conditions and reproduce platelet production in an ex-vivo bioreactor.</div>
<div></div>
<div></div>
<div>To spur development of this technology, Jonathan co-founded a company named Platelet Biogenesis. He needed support to scale the bioreactor and to develop the business strategy necessary to acquire the additional resources they needed to commercialize their technology.</div>
<div></div>
<div></div>
<div>During the B-BIC project, Jonathan and his team were able to engage an external design development group that had expertise in microfluidics to help them scale platelet production. They were also connected with industry and government experts by their supporting project manager to develop and refine their business case.</div>
<div></div>
<div></div>
<div>These efforts helped the Platelet Biogenesis team secure a $1.5 million Phase 2 SBIR award, which eventually led to additional awards and $10 million in Series A financing. Jonathan has since joined Platelet Biogenesis as their CEO and Chief Scientific Officer.</div>
<div></div>
<div></div>
<div>To learn more about Platelet Biogenesis, you can visit their website <a href="http://plateletbiogenesis.com/">here</a></div>
<div></div>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://davekuhar.github.io/bbic/2018/09/11/success-stories-b-bics-work-with-platelet-biogenesis/">Success Stories:  B-BIC&#8217;s Work With Platelet Biogenesis</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://davekuhar.github.io/bbic/">Boston Biomedical Innovation Center</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>FAST PITCH FOR FUNDING: What we are looking for when awarding B-BIC partnerships</title>
		<link>https://davekuhar.github.io/bbic/2018/08/14/fast-pitch-funding-looking-awarding-b-bic-partnerships/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[B-BIC]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 14 Aug 2018 19:10:12 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[News]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://b-bic.org/?p=989</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Potential for commercialization. Technology that addresses an unmet clinical need. Heart, Lung, Blood or Sleep indications. Preliminary data indicating promise of commercialization. Differentiation from competitors. IP filings, with institutions as the assignee. This event will provide you with the opportunity to pitch a team of experts on your research. You will receive immediate feedback with&#8230;</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://davekuhar.github.io/bbic/2018/08/14/fast-pitch-funding-looking-awarding-b-bic-partnerships/">FAST PITCH FOR FUNDING: What we are looking for when awarding B-BIC partnerships</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://davekuhar.github.io/bbic/">Boston Biomedical Innovation Center</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<header class="fl-post-header">
<div></div>
</header>
<div class="fl-post-content clearfix">
<ul>
<li>Potential for commercialization.</li>
<li>Technology that addresses an unmet clinical need.</li>
<li>Heart, Lung, Blood or Sleep indications.</li>
<li>Preliminary data indicating promise of commercialization.</li>
<li>Differentiation from competitors.</li>
<li>IP filings, with institutions as the assignee.<b><i></i></b></li>
</ul>
<p><i>This event will provide you with the opportunity to pitch a team of experts on your research. You will receive immediate feedback with the opportunity to apply for our </i><a href="https://b-bic.org/funding/"><i>grant programs</i></a><i> which can provide up to $350,000 per project, business coaching, and project management.</i></p>
<p><strong><a href="https://www.eventbrite.com/e/fast-pitch-for-funding-brigham-and-womens-hospital-tickets-71271530065">REGISTER HERE</a></strong></p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
</div>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://davekuhar.github.io/bbic/2018/08/14/fast-pitch-funding-looking-awarding-b-bic-partnerships/">FAST PITCH FOR FUNDING: What we are looking for when awarding B-BIC partnerships</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://davekuhar.github.io/bbic/">Boston Biomedical Innovation Center</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>FAST PITCH FOR FUNDING: Quick Tips for a successful pitch</title>
		<link>https://davekuhar.github.io/bbic/2018/08/14/fast-pitch-funding-quick-tips-successful-pitch-edit/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[B-BIC]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 14 Aug 2018 19:06:53 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Fast Pitch For Funding]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[News]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[FAST PITCH]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[fast pitch for funding]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://b-bic.org/?p=988</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Keep pitch short and focused on the technology and its commercial application. Limit the discussion of preliminary results, and focus on the most relevant results with conclusions – not data. Present the science within the context of the business strategy. This event will provide you with the opportunity to pitch a team of experts on your research.&#8230;</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://davekuhar.github.io/bbic/2018/08/14/fast-pitch-funding-quick-tips-successful-pitch-edit/">FAST PITCH FOR FUNDING: Quick Tips for a successful pitch</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://davekuhar.github.io/bbic/">Boston Biomedical Innovation Center</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<header class="fl-post-header"></header>
<div class="fl-post-content clearfix">
<div class="m_8149818489183255676gl-contains-text">
<table border="0" width="100%" cellspacing="0" cellpadding="0">
<tbody>
<tr>
<td class="m_8149818489183255676editor-text" align="left" valign="top">
<div></div>
<div>
<ul>
<li>Keep pitch short and focused on the technology and its commercial application.</li>
<li>Limit the discussion of preliminary results, and focus on the most relevant results with conclusions – not data.</li>
<li>Present the science within the context of the business strategy.</li>
</ul>
</div>
<p><i>This event will provide you with the opportunity to pitch a team of experts on your research. You will receive immediate feedback with the opportunity to apply for our </i><a href="https://b-bic.org/funding/"><i>grant programs</i></a><i> which can provide up to $350,000 per project, business coaching, and project management.</i></p>
<p><strong><a href="https://www.eventbrite.com/e/fast-pitch-for-funding-brigham-and-womens-hospital-tickets-71271530065">REGISTER HERE</a></strong></p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p>&nbsp;</td>
</tr>
</tbody>
</table>
</div>
</div>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://davekuhar.github.io/bbic/2018/08/14/fast-pitch-funding-quick-tips-successful-pitch-edit/">FAST PITCH FOR FUNDING: Quick Tips for a successful pitch</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://davekuhar.github.io/bbic/">Boston Biomedical Innovation Center</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
