<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	>

<channel>
	<title>Specialist Series &#8211; Boston Biomedical Innovation Center</title>
	<atom:link href="https://bbic.muellerarchive.com/category/specialist-series/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>https://bbic.muellerarchive.com/</link>
	<description></description>
	<lastBuildDate>Mon, 23 Mar 2020 15:53:31 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>
	hourly	</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>
	1	</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>https://wordpress.org/?v=5.8.1</generator>

<image>
	<url>https://bbic.muellerarchive.com/wp-content/uploads/2016/11/cropped-bbic-favicon-32x32.png</url>
	<title>Specialist Series &#8211; Boston Biomedical Innovation Center</title>
	<link>https://bbic.muellerarchive.com/</link>
	<width>32</width>
	<height>32</height>
</image> 
	<item>
		<title>Specialist Series: How To Identify The Right Inflection Points</title>
		<link>https://bbic.muellerarchive.com/2020/02/11/how-to-identify-the-right-inflection-points/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[B-BIC]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 11 Feb 2020 18:32:21 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Specialist Series]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Specialist Article]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[specialist series]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://b-bic.org/?p=1299</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Contributed by Erin McKenna, Deputy Director of B-BIC &#38; Paul Tessier, B-BIC Coach Once you understand the unmet clinical need your technology can address and have connected that need with a solid business opportunity, the next thing to be considered is to understand the development path for the product you want to create. Outlining the&#8230;</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://bbic.muellerarchive.com/2020/02/11/how-to-identify-the-right-inflection-points/">Specialist Series: How To Identify The Right Inflection Points</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://bbic.muellerarchive.com/">Boston Biomedical Innovation Center</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><em>Contributed by Erin McKenna, Deputy Director of B-BIC &amp; Paul Tessier, B-BIC Coach</em></p>
<p>Once you understand the unmet clinical need your technology can address and have connected that need with a solid business opportunity, the next thing to be considered is to understand the development path for the product you want to create. Outlining the potential path (or likely paths) forward is a necessary step for attracting funding, whether it be through grants or investors. Anyone interested in contributing resources towards developing your concept into a product will want to understand two general things. The first is understanding the resource requirements for developing your product and bringing it to the market. Second is outlining the critical steps along the way where you can gauge that you have reduced the most significant risks and that the development work will lead to a successful product. Those points are typically referred to as inflection points or milestones, and grant reviewers and savvy investors will want to know what they are and agree that they are the correct ones before they invest in developing your technology.</p>
<p>In many cases, inflection points can be true for several different types of technologies. Some common ones include:</p>
<ul>
<li>Technology development milestones including lead compound identification, or functional prototype development</li>
<li>Pre-clinical testing milestones such as pharmacokinetics study completion, toxicity studies, or completion of efficacy studies in animals (where that is possible)</li>
<li>Intellectual property milestones such as obtaining a license to patents and/or filing your patents</li>
<li>Clinical milestones such as approval of an Investigational New Drug (IND) or Investigational Device Exemption (IDE), and the completion of key clinical studies such as Phase 1, 2, and 3 studies for pharmaceuticals and biologics or safety and pivotal studies for devices</li>
<li>Regulatory milestones such as submission or acceptance of a pre-market submission, for instance, a New Drug Application (NDA) for pharmaceuticals and biologics or Pre-Market Approval (PMA) or 510k clearance for devices</li>
<li>Making the product available commercially for use, often referred to as the product launch</li>
</ul>
<p>However, assembling a plan for developing your technology must be customized to fit the needs of the product you want to develop. So, in addition to carefully understanding which of the above milestones are the most important for your product, you also need to determine where the biggest risks are for failure along the development pathway. Potential funders will be assessing risks in a range of areas, including technology, regulatory, market/business, and clinical. You can learn what the biggest risks are by gathering input from clinical users and from experts in the technology, in the market space your product will enter, in regulatory and reimbursement strategy, in market analysis, and from potential investors. The key to having productive discussions that will help you identify the most impactful inflection points will be to ask questions about the ways the development of your product could fail, and which of those ways has the highest likelihood of occurring. These things will lead you to understand the work you will need to do to convince others, especially investors, that the product you are asking for support in developing can succeed.</p>
<p>Your development plan should be broken down into phases, each phase having milestones that further reduce risks. Potential funders will want to know what their investment will be used to accomplish and how accomplishing those goals will create the next inflection point allowing you to obtain the next round of funding. The goal is to create inflection points that show both significant risk reduction and progress toward commercialization. Balancing these can sometimes be challenging. For example, you may hear a concern from potential clinical users or investors that may not be directly connected to the most critical studies needed to gain regulatory approval. To obtain the necessary support from funders, you may need to consider front-loading plans for completing the work required to address their concerns. At B-BIC, we typically work with teams to make sure they understand how potential funders think and use that input to build plans designed to address their most significant concerns as quickly as possible.</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://bbic.muellerarchive.com/2020/02/11/how-to-identify-the-right-inflection-points/">Specialist Series: How To Identify The Right Inflection Points</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://bbic.muellerarchive.com/">Boston Biomedical Innovation Center</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Specialist Series: Does Your Great Idea Have A Great Market Opportunity?</title>
		<link>https://bbic.muellerarchive.com/2020/01/13/does-your-great-idea-have-a-great-market-opportunity/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[B-BIC]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Mon, 13 Jan 2020 17:33:09 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Specialist Series]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[specialist series]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://b-bic.org/?p=1285</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Contributed by Ilsa Webeck B-BIC Skills Development Expert Developing Innovative Strategies for Leading Edge Medical Technology Companies “I have an idea. A great idea. I mean, it’s an “I can’t believe no one has thought of this before” idea. The market for this product is going to be enormous.”  In conversations with innovators spanning devices, biologics,&#8230;</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://bbic.muellerarchive.com/2020/01/13/does-your-great-idea-have-a-great-market-opportunity/">Specialist Series: Does Your Great Idea Have A Great Market Opportunity?</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://bbic.muellerarchive.com/">Boston Biomedical Innovation Center</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<div><em>Contributed by Ilsa Webeck</em></div>
<div><em>B-BIC Skills Development Expert</em></div>
<div><em>Developing Innovative Strategies for Leading Edge Medical Technology Companies</em></div>
<p>“I have an idea. A great idea. I mean, it’s an “I can’t believe no one has thought of this before” idea. The market for this product is going to be enormous.”<span class="Apple-converted-space"> </span></p>
<p>In conversations with innovators spanning devices, biologics, diagnostic tools, and many areas in between, I have heard this common refrain more times than I can count.<span class="Apple-converted-space">  </span>These conversations have even included the phrase “it is a billion-dollar market opportunity.” <span class="Apple-converted-space"> </span></p>
<p>While they intend to convey the belief that they have huge market potential and feel very strongly about the direction that they are going, they are, in fact, unintentionally signaling that they haven’t done the real work needed to understand the real opportunity. <span class="Apple-converted-space"> </span></p>
<p>Enthusiasm, excitement, and drive are all essential characteristics for an entrepreneur; however, my role is to temper this eagerness with a good dose of real market intel. All the academic preparation and focused development efforts will only go so far.<span class="Apple-converted-space">  </span>It is necessary to step out of your comfort zone to answer some critical questions about product potential before knowing if that great idea is also a commercially viable one. <span class="Apple-converted-space"> </span></p>
<p>To know the real market opportunity, and therefore revenue potential for a novel healthcare product, a key factor is to know if anyone will pay for it.<span class="Apple-converted-space">  </span>Understanding the reimbursement landscape, economic environment, and purchasing dynamics will get you on your way to understanding the real commercial opportunity.</p>
<ul>
<li><b>Reimbursement Landscape:</b> What are insurance companies and government agencies paying for similar products?<span class="Apple-converted-space">  </span>What are the direct and indirect competitors that could influence the reimbursement structure?<span class="Apple-converted-space">  </span>Will your product cause an increase or decrease in overall costs?<span class="Apple-converted-space">  </span>What are the hard costs (devices, drugs, clinic/bed space etc.) and soft costs (nursing time, improved workflow, good will, etc.) associated with using your product?<span class="Apple-converted-space">  </span><i>Pulling together these costs will give you a better picture of your pricing windows and room for margins and profitability.</i></li>
<li><b>Economic Environment</b>: What is the environment within which you would introduce the product?<span class="Apple-converted-space">  </span>Look to know the space as well as you can.<span class="Apple-converted-space">  </span>For example, is the product used in a particularly difficult type of tumor where doctors are desperate for options and insurance companies are more lenient, or would you be increasing the cost of a screening colonoscopy where margins are already razor thin?<span class="Apple-converted-space">  </span>How does this environment behave when new products are introduced?<span class="Apple-converted-space">  </span>Do they require a high degree of clinical data and peer-reviewed publications or are they willing to try something new with safety data and a few case studies?<span class="Apple-converted-space">  </span><i>The answer to these questions will help you understand the potential challenges to introduce your product in the space.</i></li>
<li><b>Purchasing Dynamics</b>: What are the conditions for hospital/clinic purchasing agents for this type of product?<span class="Apple-converted-space">  </span>Are they under any extra pressure in your area of specialization due to bundled care, close scrutiny, competitive contracts, or other reasons?<span class="Apple-converted-space">  </span>How difficult is it to get another product in your category in front of the right professionals?<span class="Apple-converted-space">  </span>What are the purchasing cycles where your product is used?<span class="Apple-converted-space">  </span><i>Knowing how your product fits into the purchasing dynamics will help you know more about potential adoption.</i></li>
</ul>
<p>Do the research to address these factors and help you better understand the market opportunity and real potential for your new product.<span class="Apple-converted-space"> </span></p>
<p>&#8212;&#8212;&#8212;&#8212;&#8212;&#8212;&#8212;&#8212;&#8212;&#8212;&#8212;&#8212;&#8212;&#8212;&#8212;&#8212;&#8212;-</p>
<p>Ilsa Webeck founded <a href="http://www.medtechstrategiesllc.com/">MedTech Strategies</a>, a boutique, strategic research consulting firm, with the knowledge that all companies, regardless of their size, need to develop a product/service value proposition and understand the business of healthcare in order to be successful. <span class="Apple-converted-space">  </span>She works with companies on new technology initiatives focused on identifying value and actionable outcomes for growth. Her past roles include corporate planning, product management and early product strategy at Johnson &amp; Johnson, Biogen and Health Advances. Ilsa holds a BA in Biology from Dartmouth College and an MBA from the Tuck School of Business.<span class="Apple-converted-space">  </span>She is an invited lecturer at the Boston Biomedical Innovation Center (B-BIC) and is a member of the board for the Medical Development Group (MDG).</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://bbic.muellerarchive.com/2020/01/13/does-your-great-idea-have-a-great-market-opportunity/">Specialist Series: Does Your Great Idea Have A Great Market Opportunity?</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://bbic.muellerarchive.com/">Boston Biomedical Innovation Center</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Specialist Series: Unmet Clinical Need</title>
		<link>https://bbic.muellerarchive.com/2019/11/14/unmet-clinical-need/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[B-BIC]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 14 Nov 2019 13:26:47 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Specialist Series]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[specialist series]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://b-bic.org/?p=1282</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Written by Paul Tessier A common refrain heard by healthcare entrepreneurs is that they should focus on satisfying an “unmet clinical need,” however there is no universal definition of the phrase, “unmet clinical need.”  Even established companies and public healthcare agencies, who use the concept of an unmet clinical need to assist in developing product&#8230;</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://bbic.muellerarchive.com/2019/11/14/unmet-clinical-need/">Specialist Series: Unmet Clinical Need</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://bbic.muellerarchive.com/">Boston Biomedical Innovation Center</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Written by Paul Tessier</p>
<p>A common refrain heard by healthcare entrepreneurs is that they should focus on satisfying an “unmet clinical need,” however there is no universal definition of the phrase, “unmet clinical need.”<span class="Apple-converted-space">  </span>Even established companies and public healthcare agencies, who use the concept of an unmet clinical need to assist in developing product roadmaps and healthcare policy, respectively, frequently struggle to gain consensus. The reason is that there are degrees of need, and the perceived importance of a need varies across the many stakeholders in the healthcare ecosystem.</p>
<p>It is generally agreed upon that there are three essential elements to consider in assessing an unmet clinical need; adequacy/availability of treatments, disease severity or burden, and size of the affected population. Related to the adequacy of treatments is the benefit of a newly proposed solution over the current treatment. Payers and value assessment committees are typically not willing to pay for an incremental increase in benefit over the existing standard of care. Diseases with high severity (e.g., morbidity &amp; mortality) and high burden (e.g., frequency &amp; cost of hospitalization) tend to get more attention and are considered more attractive needs to address. Lastly, the size of the affected population typically relates directly to the size of the business opportunity and impact of the product.<span class="Apple-converted-space"> </span></p>
<p>While healthcare entrepreneurs strive to have a positive impact on patient care, achieving that goal is only possible if they are addressing a “business-viable” unmet clinical need. This is where the product addressing the unmet clinical need can result in a profitable product-line or business. Patients, clinicians, and payers may be the target customers for your product. Still, you have other “customers” to satisfy as well – namely granting agencies and investors who will be looking at the business viability of your plan.</p>
<p>Not every unmet clinical need is a business-viable unmet clinical need. However, it is still essential to start your entrepreneurial pursuits by assessing unmet clinical needs. There is tremendous opportunity in many fields of healthcare for new devices, diagnostics, and therapeutics.</p>
<p>A new device that significantly improves efficiency and reduces costs, such as allowing treatment to move from in-patient to an out-patient procedure, will be welcomed by patients, clinicians, and payers alike. However, a new device that provides only incremental improvements will likely be challenging to get past value assessment committees or adopted by clinicians.</p>
<p><span class="Apple-converted-space"> </span></p>
<p>A new diagnostic test will be embraced if it enters a clinical domain and market that was unserved or poorly served, and it improves the quality of medical decision-making and treatment.<span class="Apple-converted-space">  </span>However, a new diagnostic test may be limited in acceptance if there is no effective treatment to implement when a diagnosis is made with the new test or if the cost of the test is too high.</p>
<p>A new drug that improves treatment and patient outcomes in an underserved clinical domain and market is likely to be adopted quickly.<span class="Apple-converted-space">  </span>However, a new drug may be adopted slowly, even in a poorly served market, if it is crowded with established standard treatments.<span class="Apple-converted-space">  </span>Treatment guidelines, conservative physicians, and payors may require that patients exhaust existing treatment options before trying the new drug.</p>
<p>Assessing the size of the market, competition, and costs associated with bringing a product to market to address an unmet clinical need will allow you to determine if it is a “business-viable” unmet clinical need.<span class="Apple-converted-space">  </span>Watch for upcoming articles in this series to help you with the next steps.</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://bbic.muellerarchive.com/2019/11/14/unmet-clinical-need/">Specialist Series: Unmet Clinical Need</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://bbic.muellerarchive.com/">Boston Biomedical Innovation Center</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Specialist Series: Technology in Search of an Application</title>
		<link>https://bbic.muellerarchive.com/2019/10/09/specialist-series-technology-in-search-of-an-application/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[B-BIC]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 09 Oct 2019 14:04:51 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Specialist Series]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[specialist series]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://b-bic.org/?p=1276</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Technology in Search of an Application Part II of the Specialist Series: The Road to Commercialization: Challenges and Opportunities Written by John Randle Development models always start with addressing clinical needs, but scientific discoveries and technological advances typically happen independently from solving clinical problems. This article will explore ways you can ensure that you are&#8230;</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://bbic.muellerarchive.com/2019/10/09/specialist-series-technology-in-search-of-an-application/">Specialist Series: Technology in Search of an Application</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://bbic.muellerarchive.com/">Boston Biomedical Innovation Center</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><strong><span data-preserver-spaces="true">Technology in Search of an Application</span></strong></p>
<p>Part II of the Specialist Series: The Road to Commercialization: Challenges and Opportunities</p>
<p>Written by John Randle</p>
<p><em><span data-preserver-spaces="true">Development models always start with addressing clinical needs, but scientific discoveries and technological advances typically happen independently from solving clinical problems. This article will explore ways you can ensure that you are connecting the promising technology you are developing, to addressing viable clinical needs.  </span></em></p>
<p><span data-preserver-spaces="true">Some visionary tech developers would have you believe that they envisioned a brave new world where their product created or filled a need that people didn’t know they had. In the reality of medical product development, this is rarely the case. The medical literature is replete with introductory paragraphs that explicitly identify medical needs, as well as others that describe how current products only partially address medical needs. The latter may be deficient in efficacy, adverse effect profile, convenience, cost and/or other characteristics. </span></p>
<p><span data-preserver-spaces="true">Opposite these medical needs is the long list of existing and emerging technologies. The key strategic insight in medical product development is the decision to orient the use of one or more technologies to the medical need(s) where they can have the highest medical impact, and as a consequence, be most likely to be commercially successful.</span></p>
<p><span data-preserver-spaces="true">In device development, new sensor and measurement technologies are frequently developed by researchers. Since the technologies are typically based on low-cost silicon processes, and are small and low power, the researches often believe the technology can revolutionize care by providing direct-to-consumer devices that can provide information to the consumer’s physicians. In reality, physicians have been skeptical of data from consumer devices and are unable to handle the volume of data provided. Applying new sensor and measurement technologies to delivering more cost-effective, rapid, and convenient measurements in the clinical setting has been much more successful.</span></p>
<p><span data-preserver-spaces="true">In diagnostic development, new biomarkers may be identified by researchers working in a specific disease area. They may attempt to demonstrate an association or causal relationship between the biomarker and particular conditions. However, apart from genetic markers of select diseases, such biomarkers may well find utility in related disease entities or entirely different specialties, sometimes more significant than in the initial indication. This may occur if the drivers of the biomarker turn out to be different from those initially expected by the researchers working in a given disease area. An example is a C-reactive protein, first identified and widely used as a marker of inflammation useful in rheumatology, but later crossing over as a diagnostic for risk of cardiac events. </span></p>
<p><span data-preserver-spaces="true">In pharmaceutical discovery and development, when a new molecular drug target is identified, researchers often hypothesize that a drug interacting with that target will have a beneficial effect in a particular therapeutic indication. However, identifying the diseases in which a targeted therapy will be useful is often impaired at this early time by incomplete knowledge of the physiology of the target. A well-known example is the phosphodiesterase-5 inhibitors that were initially studied as anti-angina drugs but were fortuitously discovered to have the potential to treat erectile dysfunction. There are many examples of targets expected to be useful in inflammatory and autoimmune diseases, as well as in oncology, which has undergone clinical testing in many indications before finding a home in one or more of these. The trick in these disease areas has been to determine in which diseases, and even in which patients, the target is a key driver of the disease and, thus, a useful drug target.  </span></p>
<p><span data-preserver-spaces="true">The unifying theme of all these examples is that researchers and product developers focused on technologies should keep open minds about how their technology can best be married to a medical need for which it can be most impactful. Conversely, researchers focused on specific medical needs to do well to scan emerging technologies to identify technologies potentially useful in their area. This is only initially an intellectual exercise. Instead, it usually plays out in the product development process, starting at the pilot/preclinical phase and ultimately requiring clinical testing to confirm the best fit between technology and medical applications.</span></p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://bbic.muellerarchive.com/2019/10/09/specialist-series-technology-in-search-of-an-application/">Specialist Series: Technology in Search of an Application</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://bbic.muellerarchive.com/">Boston Biomedical Innovation Center</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>The Road to Commercialization: Series Introduction</title>
		<link>https://bbic.muellerarchive.com/2019/09/02/the-road-to-commercialization-series-introduction/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[B-BIC]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Mon, 02 Sep 2019 14:20:59 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Specialist Series]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[specialist series]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[The road to commercialization]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://b-bic.org/?p=1245</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Written by Erin McKenna, B-BIC Deputy Director There are multiple frameworks out there that outline the process for developing promising biomedical research into a range of innovative solutions – pharmaceuticals, biologics, medical devices, and diagnostics.  Many of these processes leverage concepts that come from regulations developed by the FDA, the European Commission and others to&#8230;</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://bbic.muellerarchive.com/2019/09/02/the-road-to-commercialization-series-introduction/">The Road to Commercialization: Series Introduction</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://bbic.muellerarchive.com/">Boston Biomedical Innovation Center</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<h6><em>Written by Erin McKenna, B-BIC Deputy Director</em></h6>
<p>There are multiple frameworks out there that outline the process for developing promising biomedical research into a range of innovative solutions – pharmaceuticals, biologics, medical devices, and diagnostics.<span class="Apple-converted-space">  </span>Many of these processes leverage concepts that come from regulations developed by the <a href="https://www.healthaffairs.org/doi/pdf/10.1377/hlthaff.13.3.47">FDA</a>, the <a href="https://www.sciencedirect.com/science/article/pii/S2452302X16300638">European Commission</a> and others to evaluate the readiness of these technologies for clinical use or commercialization.<span class="Apple-converted-space">  </span>Stanford Biodesign’s <a href="http://biodesign.stanford.edu/about-us/process.html">Innovation Process</a> focuses on first ensuring that there is a thorough understanding of unmet health needs, which is a concept also described in the FDA <a href="https://www.fda.gov/media/116573/download">design control guidance</a> for medical device development.<span class="Apple-converted-space">  </span>Once enough information has been gathered to clarify the unmet needs, you can then identify potential solutions that could address them and develop and refine these concepts with input from a range of stakeholders, including clinicians and patients (broadly referred to as “users”) along with providers (such as hospitals and clinics) and payers (including, public and private insurance) to ensure that these solutions address the unmet needs.<span class="Apple-converted-space">  </span>From there you move on to evaluating other aspects such as market size, the range of potential indications and the likely regulatory path, the intellectual property landscape, competition, and the payment systems or reimbursement landscape.<span class="Apple-converted-space">  </span>This broad space is evaluated in addition to building a plan for developing the core technology and is pulled together into a comprehensive business strategy that lays out the path and identifies the necessary resources to commercialize the solution.</p>
<p>In our last <a href="https://b-bic.org/category/specialist-series/">series</a> we addressed all of the elements within a business plan for developing biotech and medtech products, which also mirrors what we request in our proposal.<span class="Apple-converted-space">  </span>However, while we ask applicants to outline a path to commercialization that may seem straightforward, we recognize that they also need to be ready to pivot their ideas as they make the transition from research to development.<span class="Apple-converted-space">  </span>All business plans are built on assumptions, and while you strive to ensure those assumptions are as solid as possible they are almost never absolute.<span class="Apple-converted-space">  </span>The road to commercialization may be clear, but it is never linear.</p>
<p>Therefore, we have decided to introduce a new series, The Road to Commercialization:<span class="Apple-converted-space">  </span>Challenges and Opportunities, on areas where our experts have observed the path is not as simple as it may appear from a distance.<span class="Apple-converted-space">  </span>Each article will focus on an area within the idealized product development process and explore the ways that teams developing solutions encounter issues while sharing insight on how to move beyond them.<span class="Apple-converted-space">  </span>We hope that this new series will complement our first series and serve as a valuable tool for helping innovators realize success.</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://bbic.muellerarchive.com/2019/09/02/the-road-to-commercialization-series-introduction/">The Road to Commercialization: Series Introduction</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://bbic.muellerarchive.com/">Boston Biomedical Innovation Center</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Specialist Series: The Breakdown of a B-BIC Proposal / Business Plan</title>
		<link>https://bbic.muellerarchive.com/2019/09/02/1241/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[B-BIC]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Mon, 02 Sep 2019 14:17:57 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[News]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Specialist Series]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Application]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[business plan]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://b-bic.org/?p=1241</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Over the course of 2019, our coaches and staff broke down the B-BIC application process to provide you with expert advice on all the of the questions we ask you to answer when applying for our program. For those who are not applying yet, the B-BIC proposal has many similarities to a business plan, which&#8230;</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://bbic.muellerarchive.com/2019/09/02/1241/">Specialist Series: The Breakdown of a B-BIC Proposal / Business Plan</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://bbic.muellerarchive.com/">Boston Biomedical Innovation Center</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Over the course of 2019, our coaches and staff broke down the B-BIC application process to provide you with expert advice on all the of the questions we ask you to answer when applying for our program. For those who are not applying yet, the B-BIC proposal has many similarities to a business plan, which we hope will be very helpful to your efforts as you proceed.</p>
<p>All Articles Within Our Series</p>
<ul>
<li><a href="https://b-bic.org/2017/10/30/build-effective-overview-technology/">How To Build An Effective Overview For Your Technology</a></li>
<li><a href="https://b-bic.org/2017/11/10/specialist-series-finding-defining-unmet-need/">Finding And Defining Your Unmet Need</a></li>
<li><a href="https://b-bic.org/2017/12/11/filling-unmet-need-proposed-solution/">Explaining Your Proposed Solution To That Unmet Need</a></li>
<li><a href="https://b-bic.org/2018/01/31/specialist-series-defining-competitive-landscape/">Defining Your Competitive Landscape</a></li>
<li><a href="https://b-bic.org/2018/03/01/specialist-series-defining-market/">Defining Your Market</a></li>
<li><a href="https://b-bic.org/2018/04/17/specialist-series-the-regulatory-path/">Regulatory Path</a></li>
<li><a href="https://b-bic.org/2018/09/11/specialist-series-a-brief-introduction-to-intellectual-property/">Intellectual Property</a></li>
<li><a href="https://b-bic.org/2018/10/19/reimbursement-basics/">Reimbursement Basics</a></li>
<li><a href="https://b-bic.org/2018/11/13/specialist-series-project-management/">Building your Project Plan</a></li>
<li><a href="https://b-bic.org/2019/01/07/understanding-and-articulating-your-financials-and-funding-requirement/">Understanding/ Articulating Your Financials And Funding Requirements</a></li>
<li><a href="https://b-bic.org/2019/02/21/venture-adventure-exploring-the-role-of-the-inventor-in-commercialization/">Defining Your Role</a></li>
</ul>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://bbic.muellerarchive.com/2019/09/02/1241/">Specialist Series: The Breakdown of a B-BIC Proposal / Business Plan</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://bbic.muellerarchive.com/">Boston Biomedical Innovation Center</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>SPECIALIST SERIES: What Is An Investible Hypothesis?</title>
		<link>https://bbic.muellerarchive.com/2019/05/26/what-is-an-investible-hypothesis/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[B-BIC]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Sun, 26 May 2019 13:55:13 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Specialist Series]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Invest]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[jay knowles]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[specialist series]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://b-bic.org/?p=783</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>By Jay Knowles Partner, Innovation Many venture capitalists look for opportunities to invest in a company or a project such that if it reaches a certain inflection point, that company will become significantly more valuable, and what it will cost to get it to that point. As an example, investors often like to see how&#8230;</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://bbic.muellerarchive.com/2019/05/26/what-is-an-investible-hypothesis/">SPECIALIST SERIES: What Is An Investible Hypothesis?</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://bbic.muellerarchive.com/">Boston Biomedical Innovation Center</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>By Jay Knowles</p>
<p>Partner, Innovation</p>
<p>Many venture capitalists look for opportunities to invest in a company or a project such that if it reaches a certain inflection point, that company will become significantly more valuable, and what it will cost to get it to that point. As an example, investors often like to see how much it will cost to take a drug discovery program from idea stage through to clinical proof of concept.</p>
<p>It helps to consider comparable examples of biotech companies in the specific field/disease indication that has been acquired by pharmaceutical companies, when they were acquired, and for how much.</p>
<p>It is also helpful to consider what intermediate steps may add value along the way, and how much funding will be required to get to those discrete points, since investors may wish to fund the company incrementally rather than all at once.</p>
<p>These incremental funding rounds are often referred to as seed, Series A, and Series B. A seed round should validate the science outside of the academic setting, possibly through in vivo proof of concept. Series A may take you through to IND stage for the lead program, and series B may take you through clinical proof of concept.</p>
<p>Taken together, these rounds of financing add up to the investment required to test the investible hypothesis. It should help venture capitalists get a sense of how strong a syndicate is necessary, and how much capital risk they will have to take on before they can get to an exit with their investment (plus hopefully some profit) returned. At BBIC, it would be helpful to understand the investible hypothesis because that will be the route to further commercialization should the proposed experiments be successful.</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://bbic.muellerarchive.com/2019/05/26/what-is-an-investible-hypothesis/">SPECIALIST SERIES: What Is An Investible Hypothesis?</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://bbic.muellerarchive.com/">Boston Biomedical Innovation Center</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Specialist Series: Venture Adventure &#8211; Exploring the Role of the Inventor in Commercialization</title>
		<link>https://bbic.muellerarchive.com/2019/02/21/venture-adventure-exploring-the-role-of-the-inventor-in-commercialization/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[B-BIC]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 21 Feb 2019 13:58:16 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[News]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Specialist Series]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Role]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[specialist series]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[venture]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://b-bic.org/?p=1197</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Written by Carl Berke, PhD. Partner at the Partners Innovation Fund Thomas Edison famously remarked, “Invention is 1% inspiration and 99% perspiration”. The Wizard of Menlo Park was a prolific inventor who never left his lab, but his intellectual property was adopted by a plethora of companies who translated his technology into products that delighted&#8230;</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://bbic.muellerarchive.com/2019/02/21/venture-adventure-exploring-the-role-of-the-inventor-in-commercialization/">Specialist Series: Venture Adventure &#8211; Exploring the Role of the Inventor in Commercialization</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://bbic.muellerarchive.com/">Boston Biomedical Innovation Center</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Written by Carl Berke, PhD.</p>
<p>Partner at the <a href="http://www.partnersinnovationfund.com/">Partners Innovation Fund</a></p>
<p>Thomas Edison famously remarked, “Invention is 1% inspiration and 99% perspiration”. The Wizard of Menlo Park was a prolific inventor who never left his lab, but his intellectual property was adopted by a plethora of companies who translated his technology into products that delighted the public. Stats from the Partners investigator community indicate more than 1000 disclosures are filed a year which yield more than 250 patents a year. About 35% of those patents eventually go under license to companies intending to develop a product protected by exclusive right to bring it to market. In most cases, the first licensee is a company at the early formation stage who wish, and often require, the participation of the inventor in the transition process and beyond. There is a continuous spectrum of options for inventor involvement that varies based on the mutual needs and desires of the founding team. The IP is the sole property of the inventor’s institution, the licensor, but any proceeds from the license are distributed, according to policy, amongst the inventors, the hospital and the inventors’ department.</p>
<p>Typically, an inventor who is part of a founder team will be offered a grant of common shares that reflects their contribution, beyond the IP creation, to the company through the arduous process of planning, fundraising, and formation. The quantity of shares [i.e., percent of company ownership] allocated is a matter of negotiation amongst the individuals of the founding team. Once the company begins operations, the inventor is often engaged as a consultant and member of the Scientific Advisory Board. The consulting contract is typically overseen by the institution to ensure compliance with conflict of interest policy. There may be additional founder equity granted to the inventor-founder as compensation for these consulting services in lieu of cash.</p>
<p>The new company will seek to recruit individuals into management with extensive industry experience who understand the protocols of drug, device, diagnostic or digital product development necessary to advance a program through the stringent FDA regulatory process. This kind of knowledge is highly specialized and generally not familiar to scientists in the academic setting and should be appreciated as comparable in importance to the success of the enterprise.</p>
<p>Academic institutional policy generally prohibits full-time employees from taking management positions in the company and limits consulting time to no more than one day/week. However, board of director service is permitted. In a few cases, faculty has crossed over to company employment usually because the stage of technology development is still so early as to require the research skills and knowledge of the inventor to ensure the success of the program. This is more common for post-doctoral fellows than PIs, but a recent case in point is Andrew Bellinger, MD, Ph.D., a cardiologist who helped to conceive a new technology platform for oral drug delivery with collaborators at MIT. Andrew recently joined Lyndra Therapeutics as Chief Scientific Officer and has led the effort to bring their first prototype to the clinic. He retains his BWH appointment so he can still spend a day a week with patients.</p>
<p>From a different context, Dr. Jonathan Thon, Ph.D., saw the potential for applying his postdoctoral research to the problem of chronic shortages in the human blood platelet supply. While working in the laboratory of Dr. Joe Italiano at BWH, he conceived a plan to develop an in vitro culture process that could be scaled up to the commercial stage. Jonathan entered the B-BIC program along with a business partner where they received additional training, coaching, and resources to create a feasibility data package and focused business plan that would attract venture investment. Jonathan transitioned out of BWH into the company, Platelet Biogenesis Inc, as Chief Executive Officer and his former PI, Dr. Italiano, serves on the Board of Directors.</p>
<p>Occasionally, a licensee company determines that the best way forward is via clinical trial directed by the original clinician-inventor. Our institutional conflict-of-interest rules prohibit investigators from conducting clinical research that is sponsored by companies in which they have any ownership. Under Harvard Medical School rules, exceptions can be granted according to the “rebuttable proposition” rule if it can be shown that there is no reasonable alternative – in those cases, special management measures are put in place to guard patient best interest. Similarly, investigators are not permitted to accept sponsored research from companies in which they hold equity as this can be considered private gain from publicly funded resources.</p>
<p>The product development pathway is a journey. It originates in the PI laboratory and at some point may cross the river of incorporation to continue on a different landscape towards the goal of market entry and actual impact on healthcare. The opportunities for inventors to participate along the way are highly situational but should be regarded as another means to fulfill both personal and professional goals. It is the mission of B-BIC to collaborate with investigators to support the creation of opportunities to transform intellectual property emerging from our research community into future products that benefit patients.</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://bbic.muellerarchive.com/2019/02/21/venture-adventure-exploring-the-role-of-the-inventor-in-commercialization/">Specialist Series: Venture Adventure &#8211; Exploring the Role of the Inventor in Commercialization</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://bbic.muellerarchive.com/">Boston Biomedical Innovation Center</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Specialist Series: Understanding And Articulating Your Financials And Funding Requirements</title>
		<link>https://bbic.muellerarchive.com/2019/01/07/understanding-and-articulating-your-financials-and-funding-requirement/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[B-BIC]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Mon, 07 Jan 2019 15:43:24 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[News]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Specialist Series]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Business Plan Series]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Specialist Article]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[specialist series]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://b-bic.org/?p=1181</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>By Lesley Watts When describing the financial support necessary to develop a technology, the first step is to be clear about the scope of the work you are addressing, as no single source of funding will be able to support all of the associated R&#38;D costs.  Anyone who is assessing your project plan will want&#8230;</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://bbic.muellerarchive.com/2019/01/07/understanding-and-articulating-your-financials-and-funding-requirement/">Specialist Series: Understanding And Articulating Your Financials And Funding Requirements</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://bbic.muellerarchive.com/">Boston Biomedical Innovation Center</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><i>By Lesley Watts</i></p>
<p>When describing the financial support necessary to develop a technology, the first step is to be clear about the scope of the work you are addressing, as no single source of funding will be able to support all of the associated R&amp;D costs.  Anyone who is assessing your project plan will want to see that you are aware of this and that you have a rough idea as to how you will continue to move forward once you have fully expended the source of support. To do this, you should begin by letting your reviewers know the aspect of the technology’s development that will be supported with the funds you are requesting.</p>
<p>Once the project plan and methods are sketched out and the associated costs can be reasonably estimated, describe the specific objectives that will be supported by these costs. Reviewers want to see the work associated with milestones and appropriate decision points. They will want to look at funds that could be re-directed should a change in the project’s course become necessary as a consequence of results obtained earlier in the project plan. For example, if a specific milestone is expected to take one-third of the project period to complete, it may be appropriate to associate one-third of the relevant personnel costs with that milestone. Similarly, if a milestone includes work that is to be conducted by an outside entity, associate the payment of that vendor with that milestone.</p>
<p>Be realistic when describing the financial requirements of the current project plan. Reviewers will want to see that the funds requested are sufficient to support the work described in the application. If you propose a scope of work that requires resources that greatly exceed your request, a reviewer may believe you are naïve, unaware of what is needed, and that you will not be able to complete the work you have described.</p>
<p>If you are planning to leverage additional resources to complete the described project plan, be sure to provide evidence of their availability. Evidence can be in the form of a letter of support from the facilities that will be contributing the additional resources, or it can be a clear-cut statement in the budget justification.  However, be sure to check with your institution or company before offering additional resources to supplement what you are requesting to support the proposed project plan. The commitment of additional resources beyond what is required by the sponsor may incur significant reporting requirements, and it may be discouraged.</p>
<p>Finally, describe how the project plan and the support requested will fit into the overall picture and development plan for the technology. The reviewers will want to know that you are aware of the follow-on work that will be needed; they will want to know that the work will not simply end when the award ends. At a high level, describe the next steps for technology development and provide a rough estimate of the costs associated with achieving the next inflection points described in the overall development plan, and be as realistic as possible.</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://bbic.muellerarchive.com/2019/01/07/understanding-and-articulating-your-financials-and-funding-requirement/">Specialist Series: Understanding And Articulating Your Financials And Funding Requirements</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://bbic.muellerarchive.com/">Boston Biomedical Innovation Center</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Specialist Series: Building Your Project Plan</title>
		<link>https://bbic.muellerarchive.com/2018/11/13/specialist-series-project-management/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[B-BIC]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 13 Nov 2018 13:57:04 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Specialist Series]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://b-bic.org/?p=1170</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Co-authored by Erin McKenna, B-BIC Deputy Director &#38; Ron Blackman, B-BIC Sr. Project Manager. When considering a development path needed to move technology to the clinic and beyond, it&#8217;s essential to address two questions:  Who will support the development of your technology, and what will they want to see to believe it can be commercialized? Who Will Support&#8230;</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://bbic.muellerarchive.com/2018/11/13/specialist-series-project-management/">Specialist Series: Building Your Project Plan</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://bbic.muellerarchive.com/">Boston Biomedical Innovation Center</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><em>Co-authored by Erin McKenna, B-BIC Deputy Director &amp; Ron Blackman, B-BIC Sr. Project Manager.</em></p>
<p>When considering a development path needed to move technology to the clinic and beyond, it&#8217;s essential to address two questions:  Who will support the development of your technology, and what will they want to see to believe it can be commercialized?</p>
<p><b>Who Will Support The Development of Your Technology?</b></p>
<p>The initial target audience for finding support is the potential investors.  This group includes government funders (for example B-BIC, SBIR, DoD or NIH), institutional grants, licensees, venture capital, angel investors and friends/ family; anyone who would be willing to provide funds for developing the product.  Potential investors may or may not include potential users of the product, such as clinicians or patients, but any product concepts you are presenting for investors will need to focus on addressing user needs and identifying key design elements their products require, as described earlier in our <a href="https://b-bic.org/?s=specialist+series">Specialist Series</a>.</p>
<p>At first, the de-risking bar will be set low (for example: providing proof of concept in animal studies, building a prototype device, or identifying a lead candidate therapeutic), but will rise quickly as development progresses (several millions of dollars will be needed to get the product to the clinic).  For an early stage therapeutic or device, the target audience / de-risking needs can and will change as the product development continues downstream.</p>
<p><b>What will they want to see to believe it can be commercialized? </b></p>
<p>At a high level your supporters want to see a combination of data that shows the potential of your technology to address a clear unmet need, along with a picture of how the technology will be developed into a product and the resources necessary to make that possible.  Each technology presents challenges, so in addition to understanding the big picture of what is needed your supporters will also have concerns that are specific to the product you intend to develop.  You can learn about these concerns by asking potential investors and users what they would need to see to believe in your product concept.  Answers to that question will likely require the completion of technical work, but may also require addressing other vital questions about how the product will be commercialized that are not technical and have been discussed in the other articles in our series.  Completing the work to address these questions is often referred to as an “inflection point,” where teams can trigger additional investment from supporters.</p>
<p>In parallel to gathering input from potential investors, imagining your future product will also help clarify your project goals and increase confidence that your product can be commercialized.  For drug candidates, teams can create a target product profile or TPP (see <a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=MdaD0URdAKw&amp;index=9&amp;list=PL_ntiNjc6GvlvOEcAmciE3MEkvs-jX7ea">Developing a Target Product Profile</a>).  Medical device product concepts capture user needs and critical design elements required to address them, referred to as Design &amp; Development Inputs or DDIs.  DDIs include a range of features which end up being captured in several separate documents (see <a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=zjm3-eKg4uU">Project Management for Medical Device Development</a>).</p>
<p>Once the project goal is more explicit, it is essential to identify milestones for measuring progress and supporting go-no-go decision points along the development path.  These will allow you to monitor that progress is being made, as well as encourage assessment at pre-defined milestones to assure that it is on track for success.  Creating benchmarks that are meaningful and based on quantifiable metrics is critical, as they will drive decisions that determine whether the work should continue according to the current project plan or if they should change course.  Key milestones should also be aligned with the inflection points described earlier, to ensure you are focused on addressing the concerns of your supporters while also enabling additional resources.</p>
<p>Once you have identified your milestones alongside your decision points, the focus shifts towards understanding the work and resources necessary to accomplish your goals. Estimating the amount of time needed to complete work towards each milestone should include elements that your team can directly control (examples:  experiment time, data analysis) along with those that are out of your control (examples:  equipment scheduling variances, production yield variabilities).  Work that is dependent on the completion of other work can impact the time needed to complete a project, and teams should evaluate how dependencies may affect the project timeline before it is finalized.  Understanding best and worst case scenarios for achieving work will help increase confidence that the project plan is realistic.</p>
<p>For an academic, building an experimental plan is one of the most familiar parts of preparing a typical grant proposal.  However, in developing a business plan, the project plan is typically more goal-oriented, and achievement is measured by meeting prescribed milestones.  When applying for early-stage development funding, proposals will request an overview and justification for each benchmark in the project plan, along with the work that will be required to achieve success.  Thus, to convince your supporters to invest it is critical to lay out a project plan that prioritizes milestones from a business planning perspective and ensures they are aligned with addressing the most significant areas of risk.</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://bbic.muellerarchive.com/2018/11/13/specialist-series-project-management/">Specialist Series: Building Your Project Plan</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://bbic.muellerarchive.com/">Boston Biomedical Innovation Center</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
