<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	>

<channel>
	<title>Press Release &#8211; Boston Biomedical Innovation Center</title>
	<atom:link href="https://davekuhar.github.io/bbic/category/press-release/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>https://davekuhar.github.io/bbic/</link>
	<description></description>
	<lastBuildDate>Mon, 08 Jan 2018 09:25:05 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>
	hourly	</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>
	1	</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>https://wordpress.org/?v=5.8.1</generator>

<image>
	<url>https://davekuhar.github.io/bbic/wp-content/uploads/2016/11/cropped-bbic-favicon-32x32.png</url>
	<title>Press Release &#8211; Boston Biomedical Innovation Center</title>
	<link>https://davekuhar.github.io/bbic/</link>
	<width>32</width>
	<height>32</height>
</image> 
	<item>
		<title>Tufts University Joins Boston Biomedical Innovation Center With Goal of  Advancing Health by Speeding New Technologies to Market</title>
		<link>https://davekuhar.github.io/bbic/2018/01/05/tufts-university-joins-boston-biomedical-innovation-center-goal-advancing-health-speeding-new-technologies-market/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[B-BIC]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 05 Jan 2018 15:28:08 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Press Release]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Consortium]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Member]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Tufts]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://b-bic.org/?p=1077</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>B-BIC’s expanding network signals the importance of forming partnerships in effort to commercialize biomedical technologies and improve healthcare. January 2018 – The Boston Biomedical Innovation Center (B-BIC), a National Center for Accelerated Innovation designed to stimulate the commercialization of biomedical technologies, today announced that Tufts University will join B-BIC as an Associate Core Member. Tufts&#8230;</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://davekuhar.github.io/bbic/2018/01/05/tufts-university-joins-boston-biomedical-innovation-center-goal-advancing-health-speeding-new-technologies-market/">Tufts University Joins Boston Biomedical Innovation Center With Goal of  Advancing Health by Speeding New Technologies to Market</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://davekuhar.github.io/bbic/">Boston Biomedical Innovation Center</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><i>B-BIC’s expanding network signals the importance of forming partnerships in effort to commercialize biomedical technologies and improve healthcare.</i></p>
<p>January 2018 – The Boston Biomedical Innovation Center (B-BIC), a National Center for Accelerated Innovation designed to stimulate the commercialization of biomedical technologies, today announced that Tufts University will join B-BIC as an Associate Core Member.</p>
<p>Tufts investigators alongside their research teams will bring extraordinary talent and aptitudes to B-BIC as they venture down the road to commercialization. They will have access to all resources offered by B-BIC – non-dilutive funding, coaching, project management, entrepreneurial skill development, and access to venture capital and B-BIC’s federal partners. The now fourteen member network works to accelerate the commercialization of biomedical technologies focused in the areas of heart, lung, blood, and sleep.</p>
<p>“We are delighted that Tufts will be joining B-BIC,”  said Joseph Loscalzo, MD, PhD, Chair, Department of Medicine at Brigham and Women’s Hospital, and Program Director of B-BIC. “Its tradition of scientific excellence and commitment to commercialization are a perfect fit.”</p>
<p>Larry Steranka, Senior Director, Office for Technology Transfer and Industry Collaboration at Tufts University, said of this new alliance, “The Tufts University community is excited to participate in the success of the National Institutes of Health-funded B-BIC, whose goal is to accelerate discoveries to benefit patient health.  B-BIC’s programs provide valuable development opportunities in entrepreneurship and innovation management that will help our researchers advance their work. The translational research awards address the biggest challenge in academic technology development and commercialization, which is the funding gap between where basic research stops and companies and investors will take on commercial investment.”</p>
<p>###</p>
<p><em>B-BIC is funded by the NIH/NHLBI under award U54HL119145 and through the institutional support provided by our member institutions.</em></p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://davekuhar.github.io/bbic/2018/01/05/tufts-university-joins-boston-biomedical-innovation-center-goal-advancing-health-speeding-new-technologies-market/">Tufts University Joins Boston Biomedical Innovation Center With Goal of  Advancing Health by Speeding New Technologies to Market</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://davekuhar.github.io/bbic/">Boston Biomedical Innovation Center</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
